<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\transforms\pp2html.xsl"?>
<PP xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/cc" name="Web Browsers">
    <PPReference title="PP Reference" id="ID003">
        <ReferenceTable>
            <PPTitle>Application Software Extended Package for Web Browsers</PPTitle>
            <PPVersion>Draft 1.1</PPVersion>
            <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
            <PPPubDate>2014-11-06</PPPubDate>
            <PPCertificationID>unassigned</PPCertificationID>
            <CCVersion>Version 3.1</CCVersion>
            <Keywords>web browser; browser</Keywords>
            <entry>
                <name>Registration</name>
                <description>National Information Assurance Partnership</description>
            </entry>
        </ReferenceTable>
    </PPReference>
    <RevisionHistory role="draft">
        <entry>
            <version>v 1.0</version>
            <date>2014-03-31</date>
            <subject>Release - Protection Profile for Web Browsers</subject>
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <version>v 2.0</version>
            <date>TBD</date>
            <subject>Draft - Application Software Extended Package for Web Browsers</subject>
        </entry>
    </RevisionHistory>
    <chapter title="Introduction" id="int">
      <section title="Overview" id="ppoverview">The scope of this Protection Profile (PP) is to
        describe the security functionality of web browsers in terms of <cite linkend="bibCC"
        />. 
      </section>
      <section title="Terms" id="glossary">The following sections provide both Common Criteria and
        technology terms used in this Protection Profile. 
        <subsection title="Common Criteria Terms" id="ccterms">
        <glossary>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Common Criteria">CC</abbr></term> 
            <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security
              Evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Common Evaluation Methodology">CEM</abbr></term>
            <description>Common Evaluation Methodology for Information Technology Security
              Evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Protection Profile">PP</abbr></term>
            <description>An implementation-independent set of security requirements for a category
              of products.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Target">ST</abbr></term>
            <description>A set of implementation-dependent security requirements for a specific
              product.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</abbr></term>
            <description>The product under evaluation. In this case, application
              software and its supporting documentation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="TOE Security Functionality">TSF</abbr></term>
            <description>The security functionality of the product under evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</abbr></term>
            <description>A description of how a <abbr linkend="TOE"/> satisfies the SFRs in a 
            <abbr linkend="ST"/>.
            </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Functional Requirement">SFR</abbr></term>
            <description>A requirement for security enforcement by the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>.
            </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Assurance Requirement">SAR</abbr></term>
            <description>A requirement to assure the security of the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>.
            </description>
          </entry>
        </glossary>
      </subsection>

      <subsection id="techterms" title="Technology Terms">
            <glossary>
                <entry>
                    <term>Active Content</term>
                    <description>code that runs in a browser, either natively or via a plug-in, without user
                        interaction</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>Administrator</term>
                    <description>The Administrator is responsible for management activities, including
                        setting the policy that is applied by the enterprise on the Browser. This
                        administrator is likely to be acting remotely. If the device is unattached
                        to an enterprise, the user is the administrator.</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>Application</term>
                    <description>software that runs on an operating system and performs tasks on behalf of
                        the user or owner of the platform</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>CSRF</term>
                    <description>Cross Site Request Forgery - Vulnerability where an attacker gets a target
                        user to execute a script with that user‘s privileges</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>DTLS</term>
                    <description>Datagram Transport Layer Security</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>Extension</term>
                    <description>bundle of code that are added to the browser to add specific functionality
                        that the browser does not provide by default</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>GPU</term>
                    <description>Graphics Processing Unit</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>HTML</term>
                    <description>HyperText Markup Language - Language used by web servers to present content
                        to browsers</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>HTML5</term>
                    <description>HyperText Markup Language version 5, a new version of HTML that incorporates
                        many new features that enrich the browsing experience</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>HTTP</term>
                    <description>HyperText Transfer Protocol - Protocol for communicating on the web</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>HTTPS</term>
                    <description>HyperText Transfer Protocol Secure; secure version of HTTP that runs over an
                        encrypted channel (SSL/TLS)</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>JavaScript</term>
                    <description>programming language commonly used as part of a web browser to enable
                        programmatic access to computational objects</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>Plug-in</term>
                    <description>browser add-on to handle specific types of web content</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>Pop-up</term>
                    <description>piece of web code that causes a browser window to open outside of the
                        browser instance that is currently in focus</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>Sandbox</term>
                    <description>Security mechanism for separating running programs, most often used to test
                        or run unverified programs that may contain malicious code without allowing
                        the programs to harm the host system</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>Tabs</term>
                    <description>allow the browsers to display content from multiple web sites without
                        starting another instance of the browser</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>Web Browser User</term>
                    <description>A user operating the TOE in unprivileged mode</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>Web Application</term>
                    <description>software application utilizing web technologies (e.g., Flash, Java, HTML)
                        that runs in a web browser or other client application</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>Web Browser</term>
                    <description>application that retrieves and renders content provided by a web server</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>Whitelist</term>
                    <description>mechanism for specifying a list of domains that are allowed to do
                        something</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>XSS</term>
                    <description>Cross Site Scripting - Vulnerability resulting from insufficient filtering
                        of special characters that allows an attacker to inject a script into a web
                        page, which is later displayed by a browser; allows the attack to deface web
                        sites or steal session information</description>
                </entry>
            </glossary>
        </subsection>
      </section>

      <section title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation" id="TOEdescription"> 
        This document provides an extended set of Security
        Functional Requirements (SFRs) for web browsers, which is the Target of Evaluation
        (TOE).
        <br/>
        The Protection Profile for Application Software defines the baseline SFRs for
        application software which runs on mobile devices ("apps") as well as on desktop and server
        platforms. This Extended Package (EP) for web browsers is not complete in itself, but rather
        extends the Protection Profile for Application Software.
        <br/>
        Web browsers are
        client applications that retrieve and render content provided by web servers, primarily
        using the hypertext transfer protocol (HTTP) or HTTP Secure (HTTPS). Browsers have grown in
        complexity over the years, starting as tools used to display simple, unchanging web pages
        and becoming sophisticated execution environments for web content. The use of browsers to
        administer accounts, servers or embedded systems remotely requires them to handle sensitive
        information securely. Innovations such as tabs, extensions and HTML5 have not only increased
        browser functionality, but also introduced new security concerns. Being the principal method
        for accessing the Internet, and due to their complexity and the information that they
        process, browsers are a natural target for attackers. As a result, it is paramount that the
        security of web browsers be improved to reduce the risk to client machines and enterprise
        networks.
        <BR/>
        This document is intended to improve the security of browsers by encouraging
        the use of operating system security services and requiring the use of sandboxing
        technologies and environmental mitigations provided by the underlying platform.
        Additionally, these requirements define security functionality that browsers themselves
        must provide.
        </section>

        <section title="Use Cases" id="usecases"> Web browsers are used to perform many tasks
            that can be categorized into three primary use cases.
             <usecases> 
                <usecase title ="Surfing the Web">
                    <description> Browsers are used to retrieve and display content on the web, such as
                    web pages, streaming media, images and specialized formats (e.g., Java, Flash,
                    Word, PDF). They can also be used to write content to web sites (web 2.0 – e.g.,
                    Facebook). Web surfing can be done over the Internet or Intranet.
                </description>
                </usecase>
            <usecase title="Remote Administration Client"> 
                <description> Browsers are used to provide remote administration interfaces for
                systems such as servers, network devices and embedded systems, such as SCADA,
                smart TVs and thermostats. As opposed to surfing the web, where the browser is
                interacting with unknown servers, the browser, acting as a Remote Administration
                Client, is connecting to a server that the user trusts. 
                </description>
            </usecase>
            <usecase title="Content Creation">  
                <description> Browsers are used to
                create content via an increasing number of Software as a Service (SaaS)
                offerings, including Microsoft Office 365, Google Drive, and Adobe Creative
                Cloud, where user data and records are stored online. 
                </description>
            </usecase>
          </usecases>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    
    <chapter title="Conformance Claims" id="conf">
        This EP is conformant to Parts 2 (extended) of Common Criteria Version 3.1, Revision 4.
    </chapter>
    
    <chapter title="Security Problem Description" id="spd">
      The security problem is described in terms of the threats that the TOE is
      expected to address, assumptions about the operational environment, and any
      organizational security policies that the TOE is expected to enforce.
        <section title="Threats" id="threattable"> The following threats should be integrated into
            the threats that are specific to the technology by the EP authors when including the
            requirements described in this document. Modifications, omissions, and additions to the
            requirements may impact this list, so the EP author should modify or delete these
            threats as appropriate. 
            <threats>
                <threat id="T.UNAUTHORIZED_ADDON">
                    <description>Malicious or exploitable extensions or plug-ins could be used knowingly or
                        unknowingly by a developer, possibly resulting in the capability of attacks
                        against the platform‘s system software.
                Web browser functionality
                can be extended with integration of third-party utilities and tools. This expanded
                set of capabilities is made possible via the use of browser plug-ins and extensions.
                The tight integration between the basic browser code and the new capabilities that
                plug-ins and extensions provide increases the risk that they could inject serious
                flaws into the browser application, either maliciously by an attacker, or
                accidentally by a developer. These flaws enable undesirable behaviors, including,
                but not limited to, allowing unauthorized access to sensitive information in the
                browser, unauthorized access to the device‘s file system, or even privilege
                escalation that enables unauthorized access to other applications or the operating
                system.
                   </description>
                </threat>
                <threat id="T.UNAUTHORIZED_UPDATE">
                    <description>Malicious or exploitable software could be used knowingly or unknowingly by
                        a developer, possibly resulting in the capability of attacks against the
                        platform‘s system software.
                Since the most common
                attack vector used involves attacking unpatched versions of software containing
                well-known flaws, updating the browser is necessary to ensure that changes to threat
                environment are addressed. Timely application of patches ensures that the client is
                a ―hard target‖, thus increasing the likelihood that product will be able to
                maintain and enforce its security policy. However, the updates to be applied to the
                product must be trustable in some manner; otherwise, an attacker can write their own
                ―update‖ that instead contains malicious code of their choosing, such as a rootkit,
                bot, or other malware. Once this ―update‖ is installed, the attacker then has
                control of the system and all of its data.

</description>
                </threat>
                <threat id="T.NETWORK_EAVESDROP">
                    <description>If positioned on a wireless communications channel or elsewhere on the
                        network, attackers may monitor and gain access to data exchanged between the
                        browser and other endpoints
                Network eavesdropping involves
                an attacker positioning himself on the network in order to monitor transmissions
                between the system and the intended destination of some potentially sensitive data.
                With respect to web browsers, this entails monitoring the transactions between the
                browser and one or more web servers, such as transmissions between a user attempting
                to pay a utility bill and the utility‘s website.
                </description>
                </threat>
                <threat id="T.NETWORK_ATTACK">
                    <description>An attacker may initiate communications with the browser or alter
                        communications between the browser and other endpoints.
            Network attack is similar to network
                eavesdropping in that it entails an attacker positioning herself on the network. It
                differs from network eavesdropping in that it involves the attacker initiating
                communications with the target system, or modifying data between the target system
                and the data‘s legitimate destination. With respect to browsers, network attack
                might involve sending malicious data to the browser in order to exploit
                vulnerabilities that may influence its behavior, or modifying account information en
                route to a web server.<br/> Browser attacks generally occur on Internet connected
                browsers, but are not unknown to occur within closed networks. Attackers can use
                phishing or another social engineering technique to persuade a user to visit a
                malicious site. Users may also unintentionally or intentionally visit malicious
                sites in the course of web browsing. The site then presents malicious content to the
                user‘s browser to exploit it and perform installation of malware, often with no
                indication to the user. These attacks depend on vulnerabilities in the browser or
                browser extensions.<br/> Some examples of network attacks are:
                <ul>
                    <li>Insufficient protection of session tokens can lead to session hijacking,
                        where a token is captured and reused in order to gain the privileges of the
                        user who initiated the session.</li>
                    <li>Cross-site scripting (XSS) and cross-site request forgery (CSRF) attacks are
                        methods used to compromise user credentials (usually by stealing the user‘s
                        session token) to a web site. These attacks are more likely a result of
                        server security problems, but some browsers incorporate technologies that
                        try to detect the attacks.</li>
                    <li>Inadequate sandboxing of browser tabs/windows or a faulty cross domain
                        communications model can lead to leakage of content from one domain (e.g.,
                        cnn.com) in one tab/window to a different domain (e.g., google.com) in a
                        different tab/window. This is an exploit of the ability of browsers to
                        display content from multiple domains simultaneously and can be carried out
                        via scripts.</li>
                </ul>
                </description>
                </threat>
                <threat id="T.DATA_ACCESS">
                    <description>Loss of confidentiality of user data and credentials may be a result of an
                        attacker gaining access to a browser while it is in operation.
                Access to a web browser while it is in
                operation may give rise to loss of confidentiality and/or integrity of user data
                stored by the web browser. Browser data such as cookie cache, history, web form
                data, etc. could be accessed by these attacks.
                </description>
                </threat>
            </threats>
        </section>
        <section title="Assumptions" id="assumptions"> The specific
            conditions listed in the following subsections are assumed to exist in the TOE's
            Operational Environment. These assumptions include both practical realities in the
            development of the TOE security requirements and the essential environmental conditions
            on the use of the TOE.<br/> ST authors should ensure that the assumptions still hold for
            their particular technology; the table should be modified as appropriate. 
            <table>
                <TR class="header">
                    <TH colspan="2">Table 1: TOE Assumptions</TH>
                </TR>
                <TR>
                    <TH>Assumption Name</TH>
                    <TH>Assumption Definition</TH>
                </TR>
                <TR>
                    <TD>A.PLATFORMS</TD>
                    <TD>The web browsers described in this document will run on any operating
                        system, regardless of the underlying platform.</TD>
                </TR>
                <TR>
                    <TD>A.TRUSTED_ADMIN</TD>
                    <TD>TOE Administrators are trusted to follow and apply all administrator
                        guidance in a trusted manner.</TD>
                </TR>
                <TR>
                    <TD>A.TRUSTED_USER</TD>
                    <TD>The Web Browser User is not malicious, and exercises appropriate
                        precautions.</TD>
                </TR>
                <TR>
                    <TD>A.PLATFORM_FUNCTIONS</TD>
                    <TD>The platform supporting the client shall offer cryptography, file system and
                        other operating system capabilities.</TD>
                </TR>
            </table>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter title="Security Objectives" id="objectives">
        <section title="Security Objectives for the TOE" id="SecurityObjectivesTOE">
            <SOs>
                <SO id="O.PROTECTED_COMMS"> 
                <description>
                To address
                the network attack and network eavesdropping threats, the TOE must provide for
                protected communications between the browser and a given web server in instances
                where such protected communications are desirable. The data between these two
                entities in the operational environment are protected via a trusted path,
                implemented using one or more of these standard protocols: HTTPS, Transport Layer
                Security (TLS) and Datagram Transport Layer Security (DTLS).<br/>
                <!-- HERE need to indent this next line, and after each objective -->
                FCS_CKM.1(*),FCS_CKM_EXT.4, FCS_COP.1(*), FCS_DTLS_EXT.1, FCS_HTTPS_EXT.1,
                FCS_TLSC_EXT.1, FCS_STS_EXT.1, FDP_STR_EXT.1, FIA_X509_EXT.1, FIA_X509_EXT.2,
                FPT_INT_EXT.3, FTP_ITC.1 
                </description>
            </SO>
            <SO id="O.ISOLATION">
                <description>
                To address the
                network attack associated with content leakage between different web domains
                rendered by the browser, the TOE must ensure that content originating from different
                domains (e.g., in a tab or iFrame) is properly isolated to disallow access.<br/>
                FDP_ACF_EXT.1, FDP_SBX_EXT.1, FDP_SOP_EXT.1 
                </description>
            </SO>
            <SO id="O.CONFIG"> 
                <description>
                In order to
                protect sensitive data stored (either temporarily or permanently) or processed by
                the browser, conformant TOEs will provide the capability to define, configure, and
                apply security policies defined by the administrator. If enterprise policies are
                configured by the administrator for the TOE, these must take precedence over any
                user-defined settings.<br/> FDP_ACC_EXT.1, FDP_TRK_EXT.1, FMT_MOF.1, FMT_SMF.1,
                FMT_SMR.1 
                </description>
            </SO>
            <SO id="O.INTEGRITY">
                <description>
                To ensure the
                integrity of the browser is maintained, conformant TOEs will perform self-tests to
                insure the integrity of software and data has been maintained.<br/> To address
                issues associated with malicious or flawed browser software, plug-ins or extensions,
                conformant TOEs must implement mechanisms to ensure the integrity of browser
                software, plug-ins and extensions, and to ensure that they come from legitimate
                sources. The TOE must provide mechanisms and enforce policies that enable any
                browser software, plug-ins and extensions, as well as any subsequent updates to
                them, to be verified upon installation and execution. In addition, the TOE shall
                also control the downloading and launching of executables.<br/> FAU_GEN.1,
                FAU_SEL.1, FCS_COP.1(2), FCS_COP.1(3), FPT_DNL_EXT.1, FPT_DNL_EXT.2, FPT_INT_EXT.1,
                FPT_INT_EXT.2, FPT_MCD_EXT.1, FPT_TUD_EXT.1, FPT_TUD_EXT.2, FPT_TUD_EXT.3 
                </description>
            </SO>
            <SO id="O.STORAGE"> 
                <description>
                Browsers handle many types of potentially sensitive user information (e.g.,
                passwords, web form data, cryptographic keys). It is critical that browsers protect
                this information when it is stored. The browser shall make use of platform
                encryption and authentication mechanisms and libraries to protect this information
                rather than mechanisms and libraries that are part of the browser itself.<br/>
                FCS_COP.1(1), FCS_CKM_EXT.1, FCS_CKM_EXT.4, FCS_COP.1(4), FDP_COO_EXT.1,
                FDP_DEL_EXT.1, FDP_DEL_EXT.2, FDP_DEL_EXT.3, FDP_PBR_EXT.1, FDP_PST_EXT.1
                </description>
            </SO>
            </SOs>
           </section>
    <!--      <section title="Security Objectives for the TOE" id="objtable">
            <table>
                <tr class="header">
                    <TH colspan="2">Table 3: Security Objectives for the TOE</TH>
                </tr>
                <TR>
                    <TH>TOE Security Objective</TH>
                    <TH>TOE Objective Definition</TH>
                </TR>
                <TR>
                    <TD>O.COMMS</TD>
                    <TD>The TOE will provide the capability to communicate using one (or more)
                        standard protocols as a means to maintain the confidentiality of data that
                        are transmitted outside of the TOE.</TD>
                </TR>
                <TR>
                    <TD>O.CONFIG</TD>
                    <TD>The TOE will provide the capability to configure and apply security
                        policies. This ensures the browser can protect user and enterprise data that
                        it may store or process.</TD>
                </TR>
                <TR>
                    <TD>O.INTEGRITY</TD>
                    <TD>The TOE will provide the capability to perform self-tests to ensure the
                        integrity of critical functionality, software/firmware and data has been
                        maintained. The TOE will also provide a means to verify the integrity of
                        downloaded updates and control the download and launch of
                    executables.</TD></TR>
                <TR>
                    <TD>O.ISOLATION</TD>
                    <TD>The TOE will provide the capability to isolate content from different
                        domains to prevent any unauthorized access.</TD>
                </TR>
                <TR>
                    <TD>O.STORAGE</TD>
                    <TD>The TOE will provide the capability to encrypt all user and enterprise data
                        and authentication keys to ensure the confidentiality of data that it
                        stores.</TD></TR>
            </table>
        </section> -->
        <section title="Security Threats to Security Objectives" id="threattoobjtable">The following
            table contains a mapping of Security Threats to Objectives for the TOE. <table>
                <TR class="header">
                    <TH colspan="2">Table 3: Security Threats to Objectives Mapping</TH>
                </TR>
                <TR>
                    <TH>Threat</TH>
                    <TH>Objective</TH>
                </TR>
                <TR>
                    <TD>T.UNAUTHORIZED_ADD-ON</TD>
                    <TD>O.INTEGRITY</TD>
                </TR>
                <TR>
                    <TD>T.UNAUTHORIZED_UPDATE</TD>
                    <TD>O.INTEGRITY</TD>
                </TR>
                <TR>
                    <TD>T.NETWORK_EAVESDROP</TD>
                    <TD>O.COMMS</TD>
                </TR>
                <TR>
                    <TD>T.NETWORK_ATTACK</TD>
                    <TD>O.COMMS; O.ISOLATION</TD>
                </TR>
                <TR>
                    <TD>T.DATA_ACCESS</TD>
                    <TD>O.STORAGE; O.CONFIG</TD>
                </TR>
            </table></section>
    </chapter>

    <chapter title="Security Requirements" id="req">This chapter describes the security requirements
        which have to be fulfilled by the TOE. Those requirements comprise functional components
        from Part 2 of <cite linkend="bibCC"/>. The following notations are used: <ul>
            <li>
                <b>Refinement</b> operation (denoted by <b>bold text</b>): is used to add details to
                a requirement, and thus further restricts a requirement.</li>
            <li>
                <b>Selection</b> (denoted by <i>italicized text</i>): is used to select one or more
                options provided by the [CC] in stating a requirement.</li>
            <li>
                <b>Assignment</b> operation (denoted by <i>italicized text</i>): is used to assign a
                specific value to an unspecified parameter, such as the length of a password.
                Showing the value in square brackets indicates assignment.</li>
            <li>
                <b>Iteration</b> operation: are identified with a number inside parentheses (e.g.
                "(1)")</li>
        </ul>
        <section title="Security Functional Requirements" id="SFR">This section addresses those
            Security Functional Requirements that may be met by the TOE. <subsection
                title="Class: User Data Protection (FDP)" id="FDP">
                <f-component id="FDP_ACF_EXT.1"
                    name="Extended: Local and Session Storage Separation">
                    <f-element id="FDP_ACF_EXT.1">
                        <title>The TOE shall separate local (permanent) and session (ephemeral)
                            storage based on domain, protocol and port:<br/>
                            <ul>
                                <li>Session storage shall be accessible only from the originating
                                    tab or window;</li>
                                <li>Local storage shall only be accessible from windows and tabs
                                    running the same web application.</li>
                            </ul></title>
                        <note role="application"> The separation of local and session storage is
                            described in World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) Proposed Recommendation:
                            “Web Storage.”<br/> In this context, a domain is a realm of
                            administrative autonomy, authority or control on the Internet (e.g.,
                            cnn.com, ietf.org). A sub-domain is denoted by a prefix before the
                            top-level domain name (e.g., news.cnn.com). A protocol is a system of
                            digital rules for data exchange within or between computers; in a web
                            environment, the typical protocols are HTTP and HTTPS. A port is an
                            application-specific construct that functions as a communications
                            endpoint in a computer’s host OS; in a web environment, port 80 is the
                            default port for HTTP communications, although other ports can be used.
                            In a web address, the port follows the domain or sub-domain name (e.g.,
                            http://www.cnn.com:80).</note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes
                            how the TSF separates local and session storage. <h4>Guidance</h4> The
                            evaluator shall examine the operational guidance to verify that it
                            documents the location on the file system that will be used for local
                            storage and the location used for session storage. <h4>Tests</h4> The
                            evaluator shall perform the following tests:<br/>
                            <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall obtain or create JavaScript-based scripts
                                    that store and retrieve information from local and session
                                    storage and shall set up a web server with two or more web pages
                                    using different protocols and/or ports. The evaluator shall
                                    incorporate the scripts into the web pages. The evaluator shall
                                    open two or more browser windows and navigate to the same web
                                    page. The evaluator shall verify that the script for accessing
                                    session storage that is running in one window cannot access
                                    session storage associated with a different window.</test>
                                <test>Using the same web server, the evaluator shall open two or
                                    more browser tabs and navigate to the same web page. The
                                    evaluator shall verify that the script for accessing session
                                    storage that is running in one tab cannot access session storage
                                    associated with a different tab.</test>
                                <test>Using the same web server, the evaluator shall open two or
                                    more browser windows and navigate to the same web page. The
                                    evaluator shall verify that the script for accessing local
                                    storage that is running in one window can access local storage
                                    associated with a different window.</test>
                                <test>Using the same web server, the evaluator shall open two or
                                    more browser tabs and navigate to the same web page. The
                                    evaluator shall verify that the script for accessing local
                                    storage that is running in one tab can access local storage
                                    associated with a different tab.</test>
                                <test>Using the same web server, the evaluator shall open windows
                                    and tabs and navigate to different web pages. The evaluator
                                    shall verify that a script running in the context of one
                                    domain/protocol/port in a window or tab cannot access
                                    information associated with a different domain/protocol/port in
                                    a different window or tab.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FDP_COO_EXT.1" name="Extended: Cookie Blocking">
                    <f-element id="FDP_COO_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The TOE shall provide the capability to block the storage of third
                            party cookies by websites.</title>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes
                            how the TSF blocks third party cookies and when the blocking occurs
                            (e.g., automatically, when blocking is enabled). <h4>Guidance</h4> The
                            evaluator shall examine the operational guidance to verify that it
                            provides a description of the configuration option for blocking of third
                            party cookies. <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator shall perform the following
                            tests: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall clear all cookies and then configure the
                                    TOE so that storage of third party cookies is allowed. The
                                    evaluator shall load a web page that stores a third party
                                    cookie. The evaluator shall navigate to the location where
                                    cookies are stored and shall verify that the cookie is
                                    present.</test>
                                <test>The evaluator shall clear all cookies and then configure the
                                    TOE so that storage of third party cookies is blocked (i.e. not
                                    allowed). The evaluator shall load a web page that attempts to
                                    store a third party cookie and shall verify that the cookie was
                                    not stored.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FDP_DEL_EXT.1" name="Extended: Deletion of Browser Data">
                    <f-element id="FDP_DEL_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The TOE shall provide the capability to delete <selectables>
                                <selectable>browser cache</selectable>
                                <selectable>history</selectable>
                                <selectable>passwords</selectable>
                                <selectable>web form information</selectable>
                                <selectable>cookies</selectable>
                                <selectable>extensions</selectable>
                                <selectable>plug-ins</selectable>
                            </selectables> from the TOE when invoked by the user.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FDP_DEL_EXT.1.2">
                        <title>The TOE shall provide the capability to delete <selectables>
                                <selectable>browser cache</selectable>
                                <selectable>history</selectable>
                                <selectable>passwords</selectable>
                                <selectable>web form information</selectable>
                                <selectable>cookies</selectable>
                                <selectable>extensions</selectable>
                                <selectable>plug-ins</selectable>
                            </selectables> from the TOE when the browser is terminated.</title>
                        <note role="application"> If extensions or plug-ins are selected above, the
                            applicable selection-based requirements from Annex C must also be
                            included in the main body of the ST. </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it
                            documents where all browser content is stored and what browser content
                            can be deleted. The TSS shall also describe the deletion of browser
                            content when the browser is terminated. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator
                            shall examine the operational guidance to verify that it includes
                            instructions for how the user can delete stored content and select which
                            types of stored content can be deleted. The operational guidance shall
                            also include instructions for ensuring that content is deleted upon
                            browser termination. <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall perform the
                            following tests for each type of stored content: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall set up a web session with a web server
                                    that prompts the creation and storage of stored content. The
                                    evaluator shall verify that the supported type of content is
                                    stored in the documented location. The evaluator shall then
                                    delete content via the browser and shall verify that the stored
                                    content has been deleted from the documented location.</test>
                                <test>The evaluator shall verify that browser content is in the
                                    specified location. The evaluator shall invoke the TOE, set it
                                    to delete content, and shall terminate the TOE. The evaluator
                                    shall navigate to the documented location of the content and
                                    verify that the stored content has been deleted.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FDP_SBX_EXT.1" name="Extended: Sandboxing of Rendering Processes">
                    <f-element id="FDP_SBX_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The TOE shall ensure that web page rendering is performed in a
                            process that is restricted in the following manner: <ul>
                                <li>The rendering process cannot directly access the TOE platform's
                                    file system;</li>
                                <li>The rendering process cannot directly invoke inter-process
                                    communication mechanisms with non-TOE processes;</li>
                                <li>The rendering process has reduced privilege with respect to
                                    other TOE processes <selectables>
                                        <selectable>[assignment: methods by which the principle of
                                            least privilege is implement for rendering
                                            processes]</selectable>
                                        <selectable>in no other ways</selectable>
                                    </selectables></li>
                            </ul>
                        </title>
                        <note role="application"> Web browsers implement a variety of methods to
                            ensure that the process that renders HTML and interprets JavaScript
                            operates in a constrained environment in order to reduce the risk that
                            the rendering process can be corrupted by the HTML or JavaScript it is
                            processing. This component requires the TSF to lower the privileges of
                            rendering processes by ensuring that it cannot directly access the file
                            system of the host, and that it cannot use IPC mechanisms provided by
                            the host to communicate with non-TOE processes on the host. Typically,
                            if a rendering process needs to access a file or communicate with a
                            non-TOE process, it must request such access through the TSF (which is
                            allowed by the requirement).<br/> In addition to the two required
                            measures, other measures can be implemented depending on the TOE and the
                            host platform. These may involve such actions as changing the owner of
                            the rendering process to a low-privileged account or dropping
                            platform-defined privileges in the rendering process. The ST author
                            fills in the additional measures implemented by the TOE. </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes
                            how the rendering of HTML and interpretation of JavaScript is performed
                            by the TOE in terms of the platform processes that are involved (with
                            "process" being an active entity that executes code). For the processes
                            that render HTML or interpret JavaScript, the evaluator shall examine
                            the TSS to check that it describes how these processes are prevented
                            from accessing the platform file system. The evaluator shall check the
                            TSS to ensure it describes each platform-provided IPC mechanism, and
                            details for each mechanism how the rendering process is unable to use it
                            to communicate with non-TOE processes. The evaluator shall also confirm
                            that the TSS describes how IPC and file system access is enabled (if
                            this capability is implemented); for instance, through a more privileged
                            TOE process that does not perform web page rendering. The evaluator
                            shall ensure that these descriptions are present for all platforms
                            claimed in the ST.<br/> For each additional mechanism listed in the
                            third bullet of this component by the ST author, the evaluator shall
                            examine the TSS to ensure 1) the mechanisms is described; 2) the
                            description of the mechanism is sufficiently detailed to determine that
                            it contributes to the principle of least privilege being implemented in
                            the rendering process; and 3) appropriate supporting information is
                            provided in the TSS (or pointers to such information are provided) that
                            provides context for understanding the claimed least privilege
                            mechanisms. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the
                            operational guidance to determine that it provides a description of the
                            restrictions available on rendering processes. Additionally, if such
                            mechanisms are configurable (for instance, if a user can choose which
                            mechanisms to "turn on"), the evaluator shall examine the operational
                            guidance to ensure that the method for enabling and disabling the
                            mechanisms are provided, and the consequences of such actions are
                            described. <h4>Tests</h4>Note: The following tests require the developer
                            to provide access to a test platform that provides the evaluator with
                            debugging and test tools that are typically not found on consumer
                            platforms.<br/> The evaluator shall perform the following tests on each
                            platform claimed in the ST: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall use debugging or test facilities to
                                    introduce code into a rendering process that attempts to
                                    directly access the platform's file system, and then direct
                                    execution to it. The evaluator shall ensure that execution of
                                    this code fails to access the TOE file system.</test>
                                <test>For each IPC mechanism described in the TSS, the evaluator
                                    shall use debugging or test facilities to introduce code into a
                                    rendering process that attempts to directly communicate with
                                    another non-TOE process on the platform, and then direct
                                    execution to it. The evaluator shall ensure that this attempt
                                    fails.</test>
                                <test>For each additional mechanism claimed in the ST, the evaluator
                                    shall devise a test to show that the mechanism functions as
                                    described in the TSS. If no such test can be crafted, the
                                    evaluator shall provide a justification in the test report for
                                    why the mechanism cannot be tested.</test>
                                <test>For each mechanism that can be configured or turned on or off,
                                    the evaluator shall perform tests to ensure that the
                                    configuration of the mechanism behaves as specified in the
                                    operational guidance.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FDP_SOP_EXT.1" name="Extended: Same Origin Policy">
                    <f-element id="FDP_SOP_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The TOE shall ensure that content retrieved from one origin cannot
                            interact with content retrieved from another origin without consent from
                            the origin whose content is being retrieved.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FDP_SOP_EXT.1.2 The TOE">
                        <title>shall not allow same origin policy exceptions for different
                            domains.</title>
                        <note role="application"> The Same Origin Policy concept is described in RFC
                            6454, “The Web Origin Concept.”<br/> Origin is defined as the
                            combination of domain, protocol and port. Two URIs sharing the same
                            domain, protocol and port are considered to have the same origin. </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes
                            its implementation of a same origin policy and explains how it complies
                            with RFC 6454. If the TSF allows the relaxation of the same origin
                            policy for subdomains in different tabs or windows, the TSS shall
                            describe how these exceptions are implemented. <h4>Guidance</h4> N/A
                                <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall perform the following tests: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall obtain or create scripts that can retrieve
                                    content from designated locations and shall set up a web server
                                    with two or more web pages representing different domains. The
                                    evaluator shall incorporate the scripts into the web pages. The
                                    evaluator shall associate each page with a different protocol
                                    and/or port. The evaluator shall open two or more browser
                                    windows and navigate to a different page on the website in each
                                    window. The evaluator shall run the scripts and shall verify
                                    that the script that is running in one window cannot access
                                    content that was retrieved in a different window.</test>
                                <test>Using the same web server, the evaluator shall open two or
                                    more browser tabs and navigate to a different page on the
                                    website in each tab. The evaluator shall run the scripts and
                                    shall verify that the script that is running in one tab cannot
                                    access content that was retrieved in a different tab.</test>
                                <test>If the TSF supports relaxation of the same origin policy for
                                    subdomains, the evaluator shall configure the web server with
                                    subdomains and shall repeat tests 1 and 2. The evaluator shall
                                    verify that the scripts can retrieve content from another
                                    window/tab at a different subdomain.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FDP_STR_EXT.1" name="Extended: Secure Transmission of Cookie Data">
                    <f-element id="FDP_STR_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The TOE shall ensure that cookies containing the ―secure‖ attribute
                            in the set-cookie header are sent over HTTPS.</title>
                        <note role="application"> The set-cookie header functionality is described
                            in RFC 6265, “HTTP State Management Mechanism.” </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify it describes
                            the TOE‘s support for the ―secure‖ attribute of the set-cookie header in
                            accordance with RFC 6265, including the required sending of cookies
                            containing this attribute over HTTPS. <h4>Guidance</h4> N/A
                                <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall perform the following tests: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall connect the TOE to a cookie-enabled test
                                    website implementing HTTPS and have the website present the TOE
                                    with a ―secure‖ cookie. The evaluator shall examine the TOE‘s
                                    cookie cache and verify that that it contains the secure
                                    cookie.</test>
                                <test>The evaluator shall reconnect to the cookie-enabled website
                                    over an insecure channel and verify that no ―secure‖ cookie is
                                    sent.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FDP_TRK_EXT.1" name="Extended: Tracking Information Collection">
                    <f-element id="FDP_TRK_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The TOE shall support the ability of websites to collect <selectables>
                                <selectable>web sites accessed</selectable>
                                <selectable>geo-location information</selectable>
                                <selectable>system configuration</selectable>
                                <selectable>system status</selectable>
                                <selectable>error conditions</selectable>
                                <selectable>crash conditions</selectable>
                                <selectable>[assignment: other tracking information]</selectable>
                            </selectables> pertaining to the TOE user.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FDP_TRK_EXT.1.2">
                        <title>The TOE shall provide notification to the user when tracking
                            information is requested by a website.</title>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes
                            the TSF‘s support for tracking information and specifies the tracking
                            information that the TOE allows websites to collect about the TOE user.
                                <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the operational
                            guidance to ensure it describes any notifications that the user will
                            receive when tracking information is requested by a website and the
                            options that the user has upon receiving the notification.
                                <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall perform the following tests for
                            each type of tracking information listed in the TSS: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall configure a website that requests the
                                    tracking information about the user and shall navigate to that
                                    website. The evaluator shall verify that the user is notified
                                    about the request for tracking information and that, upon
                                    consent, the web site retrieves the tracking information.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
            </subsection>
            <subsection title="Class: Protection of the TSF (FPT)" id="fpt">
                <f-component id="FPT_DNL_EXT.1" name="Extended: Launch of Downloaded Executables">
                    <f-element id="FPT_DNL_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The TOE shall prevent downloaded executables from launching
                            automatically.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FPT_DNL_EXT.1.2">
                        <title>The TOE shall present the user with the option to either download or
                            discard the executable.</title>
                        <note role="application"> In this context, an executable is a file
                            containing compiled code for a software program that, when launched,
                            initiates the installation of the program. It is invoked independent of
                            and outside the context of the TOE. It does not include mobile code,
                            scripts, or plug-ins.<br/> This requirement does not include the
                            invocation of any program that is already installed on the TOE
                            platform.<br/> This requirement ensures that if the user intentionally
                            (via clicking on a link) or unintentionally initiates the download of an
                            executable, the TSF will intervene by, for example, opening a dialog box
                            that presents the user with the option to either save the executable to
                            the file system or not download the executable. </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it
                            describes the behavior of the TSF when a user initiates the download of
                            an executable. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the
                            operational guidance to ensure it describes the dialog box that appears
                            when a download is initiated and the implications of the options
                            presented by the dialog box. <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall perform
                            the following tests: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall navigate to a website that hosts
                                    executables and shall attempt to download and launch several
                                    executables. The evaluator shall verify that the TOE always
                                    presents a dialog box with the option to either download the
                                    executable to the file system or discard the executable.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FPT_DNL_EXT.2" name="Extended: Download Location">
                    <f-element id="FPT_DNL_EXT.2.1">
                        <title>The TOE shall have the capability to specify where downloads are
                            saved.</title>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> N/A <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the
                            operational guidance to ensure it describes the default location for
                            downloads and instructions for modifying the location. <h4>Tests</h4>The
                            evaluator shall perform the following tests: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall navigate to a website that serves files
                                    and shall to download a file. The evaluator shall inspect the
                                    default location specified in the operational guidance and shall
                                    verify that the download is present.</test>
                                <test>The evaluator shall modify the location where downloaded files
                                    are saved. The evaluator shall attempt to download a file from a
                                    website that serves files and shall verify that the file is
                                    saved to the configured location.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FPT_INT_EXT.1"
                    name="Extended: Interactions with Background Processes">
                    <f-element id="FPT_INT_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The TOE shall shut down any TOE-spawned background processes when the
                            TOE exits.</title>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes
                            all TOE-spawned processes that run while the TOE is running and
                            describes the ability to terminate these processes when the TOE exits.
                            The TSS should also describe the nature of the background processes, the
                            circumstances under which they are spawned, the process/image names
                            associated with them (if any) and their expected lifetimes.
                                <h4>Guidance</h4> N/A <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall perform the
                            following tests: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall start an instance of the TOE. The
                                    evaluator shall inspect the TOE platform‘s running processes and
                                    identify which are associated with the TOE instance. The
                                    evaluator shall shut down the TOE instance and verify that the
                                    TOE background processes have been terminated.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FPT_MCD_EXT.1" name="Extended: Mobile Code">
                    <f-element id="FPT_MCD_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The TOE shall support the capability to execute signed <selectables>
                                <selectable>ActiveX</selectable>
                                <selectable>Flash</selectable>
                                <selectable>Java</selectable>
                                <selectable>JavaScript</selectable>
                                <selectable>[assignment: other mobile code types supported by the
                                    TOE]</selectable>
                            </selectables>mobile code.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FPT_MCD_EXT.1.2">
                        <title>The TOE shall support the capability to execute unsigned <selectables>
                                <selectable>ActiveX</selectable>
                                <selectable>Flash</selectable>
                                <selectable>Java</selectable>
                                <selectable>JavaScript</selectable>
                                <selectable>[assignment: other mobile code types supported by the
                                    TOE]</selectable>
                            </selectables> mobile code.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FPT_MCD_EXT.1.3">
                        <title>The TOE shall support the capability to execute <selectables>
                                <selectable>ActiveX</selectable>
                                <selectable>Flash</selectable>
                                <selectable>Java</selectable>
                                <selectable>JavaScript</selectable>
                                <selectable>[assignment: other mobile code types supported by the
                                    TOE]</selectable>
                            </selectables> mobile code from an untrusted or unverified
                            source.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FPT_MCD_EXT.1.3">
                        <title>The TOE shall notify the user when unsigned, untrusted or unverified
                            mobile code is encountered.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FPT_MCD_EXT.1.4">
                        <title>The TOE shall provide the user with the option to discard unsigned,
                            untrusted or unverified mobile code without executing it.</title>
                        <note role="application"> The ST writer must specify all mobile code types
                            that are supported by the browser. If they are not listed, the ST writer
                            must fill in the assignment with the mobile code types that are
                            missing.<br/> An authorized signer may directly sign the code itself, or
                            the code may be delivered over an authenticated HTTPS connection with an
                            authorized entity.<br/> The execution of signed mobile code is specified
                            by FIA_X509_EXT.2. </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it lists the
                            types of signed mobile code that the TSF supports. The TSS shall
                            describe how the TSF handles unsigned mobile code, mobile code from an
                            untrusted source, and mobile code from an unverified source.
                                <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the operational
                            guidance to verify it provides configuration instructions for each of
                            the supported mobile code types. The operational guidance shall also
                            describe the alert that the TOE displays to the user when unsigned,
                            untrusted, or unverified mobile code is encountered and the actions the
                            user can take. <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall perform the following
                            tests for each mobile code type specified in the TSS: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall construct web pages containing unsigned,
                                    correctly authenticated, and incorrectly authenticated mobile
                                    code and ensure that the TOE alerts the user when it encounters
                                    mobile code that fails to authenticate and provides the user
                                    with the option to discard the mobile code without executing it,
                                    but does execute mobile code that properly authenticates.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section title="TOE or TOE Platform Security Functional requirements" id="TOESFR">This
            section addresses Security Functional Requirements that may be met by either the TOE
            itself, by the TOE platform, or by a combination of the TOE and the TOE platform.
                <subsection title="Class: Cryptographic Support (FCS)" id="FCS">
                <!--need to check to see is Zeriozation is addressed in App on OS. If yes, removed from this EP-->
                <f-component id="FCS_CKM_EXT.4" name="Extended: Cryptographic Key Zeroization">
                    <f-element id="FCS_CKM_EXT.4.1">
                        <title>The <selectables>
                                <selectable>TOE</selectable>
                                <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
                            </selectables> shall zeroize all plaintext secret and private
                            cryptographic keys and CSPs when no longer required.</title>
                        <note role="application"> The ST author should select the platform if the
                            Web Browser performs no operations using plaintext secret, private
                            cryptographic keys, and CSPs.<br/> Any security related information
                            (such as keys, authentication data, and passwords) must be zeroized when
                            no longer in use to prevent the disclosure or modification of security
                            critical data.<br/> The zeroization indicated above applies to each
                            intermediate storage area for plaintext key and Cryptographic Service
                            Provider (CSP) (i.e., any storage, such as memory buffers, that is
                            included in the path of such data) upon the transfer of the key/CSP to
                            another location.<br/>
                        </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4>
                            <u>Requirement met by TOE platform:</u> The evaluator shall check to
                            ensure the TSS describes each of the secret keys (keys used for
                            symmetric encryption), private keys, and CSPs used to generate key that
                            are not otherwise covered by the FCS_CKM_EXT.4 requirement levied on the
                            TOE. For each platform listed in the ST, the evaluator shall examine the
                            TSS of the ST of the platform to ensure that each of the secret keys,
                            private keys, and CSPs used to generate key listed above are covered.<br/>
                            <u>Requirement met by TOE:</u> The evaluator shall check to ensure the
                            TSS describes each of the secret keys (keys used for symmetric
                            encryption) and private keys, as well as the CSPs used to generate key;
                            when the keys are zeroized (for example, immediately after use, on
                            system shutdown, etc.); and the type of zeroization procedure that is
                            performed (overwrite with zeros, overwrite three times with random
                            pattern, etc.). If different types of memory are used to store the
                            materials to be protected, the evaluator shall check to ensure that the
                            TSS describes the zeroization procedure in terms of the memory in which
                            the data are stored (for example, "secret keys stored in volatile memory
                            are zeroized by overwriting once with zeros, while secret keys stored on
                            the internal hard drive are zeroized by overwriting three times with a
                            random pattern that is changed before each write"). If a read-back is
                            done to verify the zeroization, this shall be described as well.<br/>
                            <h4>Guidance</h4> N/A <h4>Tests</h4>
                            <i><b>Assurance Activity Note:</b> The following tests require the
                                developer to provide access to a test platform that provides the
                                evaluator with tools that are typically not found on consumer
                                platforms.</i><br/>
                            <u>Requirement met by TOE:</u> For each key clearing situation described
                            in the TSS the evaluator shall repeat the following test.<br/>
                            <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall utilize appropriate combinations of
                                    specialized operational environment and development tools
                                    (debuggers, simulators, etc.) for the TOE and instrumented TOE
                                    builds to test that keys are cleared correctly, including all
                                    intermediate copies of the key that may have been created
                                    internally by the TOE during normal cryptographic processing
                                    with that key.<br/> Cryptographic TOE implementations in
                                    software shall be loaded and exercised under a debugger to
                                    perform such tests. The evaluator shall perform the following
                                    test for each key subject to clearing, including intermediate
                                    copies of keys that are persisted encrypted by the TOE:<br/>
                                    <ul>
                                        <li>Load the instrumented TOE build in a debugger.</li>
                                        <li>Record the value of the key in the TOE subject to
                                            clearing.</li>
                                        <li>Cause the TOE to perform a normal cryptographic
                                            processing with the key from #1.</li>
                                        <li>Cause the TOE to clear the key.</li>
                                        <li>Cause the TOE to stop the execution but not exit.</li>
                                        <li>Cause the TOE to dump the entire memory footprint of the
                                            TOE into a binary file.</li>
                                        <li>Search the content of the binary file created in #4 for
                                            instances of the known key value from #1.</li>
                                    </ul> The test succeeds if no copies of the key from #1 are
                                    found in step #7 above and fails otherwise.<br/> The evaluator
                                    shall perform this test on all keys, including those that
                                    persist in encrypted form, to ensure intermediate copies are
                                    cleared.</test>
                                <test>In cases where the TOE is implemented in firmware and operates
                                    in a limited operating environment that does not allow the use
                                    of debuggers, the evaluator shall utilize a simulator for the
                                    TOE on a general purpose operating system. The evaluator shall
                                    provide a rationale explaining the instrumentation of the
                                    simulated test environment and justifying the obtained test
                                    results.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
            </subsection>
            <subsection title="Class: Identification and Authentication (FIA)" id="fia">
                <f-component id="FIA_X509_EXT.2" name="Extended: X509 Authentication">
                    <f-element id="FIA_X509_EXT.2.3">
                        <title>The <selectables>
                                <selectable>TOE</selectable>
                                <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
                            </selectables> shall notify the user if the peer certificate is deemed
                            invalid during trusted communication channel establishment.</title>
                        <note role="application"> Trusted communication channels include any of TLS,
                            HTTPS, or DTLS performed by the TSF or TOE platform. Validity is
                            determined by the certificate path, the expiration date, and the
                            revocation status in accordance with RFC 5280. </note>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FIA_X509_EXT.2.4">
                        <title>The <selectables>
                                <selectable>TOE</selectable>
                                <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
                            </selectables> shall not install code if the code signing certificate is
                            deemed invalid.</title>
                        <note role="application"> Certificates may optionally be used for trusted
                            updates of system software (FPT_TUD_EXT.1.3). </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it
                            describes how the TOE chooses which certificates to use.<br/> The
                            evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it describes the behavior
                            of the TOE or TOE platform when a connection cannot be established
                            during the validity check of a certificate used in establishing a
                            trusted channel. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall verify that any
                            necessary instructions are contained in the operational guidance for
                            configuring the operating environment so that the TOE can use the
                            certificates.<br/> If the requirement is that the administrator is able
                            to specify the default action, then the evaluator shall ensure that the
                            operational guidance contains instructions on how this configuration
                            action is performed. <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator shall perform Test 1
                            for each function listed in FIA_X509_EXT.2.1 that requires the use of
                            certificates: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall demonstrate that using a certificate
                                    without a valid certification path results in the function
                                    failing or in the receipt of a user notification (as required by
                                    elements 3 and 4). The evaluator shall then load into the
                                    platform‘s root store any certificates needed to validate the
                                    certificate to be used in the function, and demonstrate that the
                                    function succeeds.</test>
                                <test>The evaluator shall demonstrate that using a valid certificate
                                    that requires certificate validation checking to be performed in
                                    at least some part by communicating with a non-TOE IT entity.
                                    The evaluator shall then manipulate the environment so that the
                                    TOE is unable to verify the validity of the certificate, and
                                    observe that the action selected in FIA_X509_EXT.2.2 is
                                    performed. If the selected action is administrator-configurable,
                                    then the evaluator shall follow the operational guidance to
                                    determine that all supported administrator-configurable options
                                    behave in their documented manner.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
            </subsection>
            <subsection title="Class: Security Management (FMT)" id="fmt">
                <f-component id="FMT_MOF.1" name="Management of Functions Behavior">
                    <f-element id="FMT_MOF.1.1">
                        <title>The <selectables>
                                <selectable>TOE</selectable>
                                <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
                            </selectables> shall restrict the ability to perform the functions: <ol>
                                <li>enable/disable storage of sensitive web form information;</li>
                                <li>configuration of mobile code:</li>
                                <ol>
                                    <li>ability to install mobile code;</li>
                                    <li>ability to uninstall mobile code;</li>
                                    <li>ability to update mobile code;</li>
                                    <li>ability to execute unsigned mobile code;</li>
                                    <li>ability to execute mobile code from an untrusted or
                                        unverified publisher</li>
                                </ol>
                                <selectables linebreak="yes">
                                    <selectable><li>enable/disable storage of third party
                                            cookies;</li></selectable>
                                    <selectable><li>configuration of extensions:</li></selectable>
                                    <ol>
                                        <selectable><li>ability to install
                                            extensions;</li></selectable>
                                        <selectable><li>ability to uninstall
                                            extensions;</li></selectable>
                                        <selectable><li>ability to update
                                            extensions;</li></selectable>
                                        <selectable><li>ability to disable
                                            extensions</li></selectable>
                                    </ol>
                                    <selectable><li>configuration of plug-ins:</li></selectable>
                                    <ol>
                                        <selectable><li>ability to install
                                            plug-ins;</li></selectable>
                                        <selectable><li>ability to uninstall
                                            plug-ins;</li></selectable>
                                        <selectable><li>ability to update
                                            plug-ins;</li></selectable>
                                        <selectable><li>ability to disable
                                            plug-ins</li></selectable>
                                    </ol>
                                    <selectable><li>enable/disable use of OCSP for obtaining the
                                            revocation status of an X.509
                                        certificate;</li></selectable>
                                    <selectable><li>configure inclusion of user-agent information in
                                            HTTP headers;</li></selectable>
                                    <selectable><li>enable/disable ability for websites to collect
                                            tracking information about the user</li></selectable>
                                    <selectable><li>deletion of stored browsing data (cache, web
                                            form information):</li></selectable>
                                    <ol>
                                        <selectable><li>ability to specify which content should be
                                                deleted;</li></selectable>
                                        <selectable><li>ability to delete all stored
                                            content;</li></selectable>
                                        <selectable><li>automatically delete content upon
                                                termination of the browser
                                            session;</li></selectable>
                                    </ol>
                                    <selectable><li>enable/disable storage of sensitive information
                                            in persistent storage;</li></selectable>
                                    <selectable><li>ability to specify location where downloaded
                                            files are saved to disk;</li></selectable>
                                    <selectable><li>configure size of cookie
                                        cache;</li></selectable>
                                    <selectable><li>enable/disable interaction with Graphic
                                            Processing Units (GPUs)</li></selectable>
                                    <selectable><li>configure the ability to advance to a web site
                                            with an invalid or unvalidated X.509
                                        certificate;</li></selectable>
                                    <selectable><li>enable/disable use of private browsing
                                            sessions;</li></selectable>
                                    <selectable><li>configure the use of an application reputation
                                            service to detect malicious applications prior to
                                            downloading them;</li></selectable>
                                    <selectable><li>configure the use of a URL reputation service to
                                            detect sites that contain malware or phishing
                                            content;</li></selectable>
                                    <selectable><li>enable/disable automatic installation of
                                            software updates and patches;</li></selectable>
                                    <selectable><li>enable/disable establishment of a trusted
                                            channel if the TSF cannot establish a connection to
                                            determine the validity of a
                                        certificate;</li></selectable>
                                    <selectable><li>enable/disable ability for websites to register
                                            protocol handlers.</li></selectable>
                                </selectables>
                            </ol> to an administrator according to the administrator policy. </title>
                        <note role="application"> The intent of this requirement is to allow the
                            administrator of the TOE platform to configure the TOE with a policy
                            that may not be over-ridden by the user. If the administrator has not
                            set a policy for a particular function, the user may still perform that
                            function. Enforcement of the policy is done by the TOE itself, or the
                            TOE and the TOE platform in coordination with each other </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall verify that the TSS describes those
                            management functions which may only be configured by the TOE platform
                            administrator and cannot be over-ridden by the user when set according
                            to policy. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the operational
                            guidance to verify that it includes instructions for a TOE platform
                            administrator to configure the functions listed in FMT_MOF.1.1.
                                <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall perform the following test:<br/>
                            <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall create policies that collectively include
                                    all management functions controlled by the TOE platform
                                    administrator and cannot be over-ridden by the user as defined
                                    in FMT_MOF.1.1. The evaluator shall apply these policies to the
                                    TOE, attempt to override each setting as the user, and verify
                                    that the TSF does not permit it.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FMT_SMR.1" name="Security Management Roles">
                    <f-element id="FMT_SMR.1.1">
                        <title>The <selectables>
                                <selectable>TOE</selectable>
                                <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
                            </selectables> shall maintain the roles: Administrator.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FMT_SMR.1.2">
                        <title>The <selectables>
                                <selectable>TOE</selectable>
                                <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
                            </selectables> shall be able to associate users with roles.</title>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS and user documents to
                            verify that they describe the administrator role and the powers granted
                            to and limitations of the role. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall
                            examine the operational guidance to ensure that it contains instructions
                            for administering the TOE and which interfaces are supported.
                                <h4>Tests</h4> In the course of performing the testing activities
                            for the evaluation, the evaluator shall use all supported interfaces,
                            although it is not necessary to repeat each test involving an
                            administrative action with each interface. The evaluator shall ensure,
                            however, that each supported method of administering the TOE that
                            conforms to the requirements of this EP be tested; for instance, if the
                            TOE can be administered through a local hardware interface or TLS/HTTPS
                            then both methods of administration must be exercised during the
                            evaluation team‘s test activities. </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
            </subsection>
            <subsection title="Class: Protection of the TSF (FPT)" id="tsffpt">
                <f-component id="FPT_TST_EXT.1" name="Extended: TSF Self-Test">
                    <f-element id="FPT_TST_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The <selectables>
                                <selectable>TOE</selectable>
                                <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
                            </selectables> shall run a suite of self-tests during initial start-up
                            (on power on) to ensure the integrity of its executable and
                            data.</title>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it
                            specifies the self-tests that are performed at start-up; this
                            description should include an outline of what the tests are actually
                            doing (e.g., verifying the integrity of the TOE executable). The TSS
                            must include any error states that the TSF or TOE platform may enter
                            when self-tests fail, and the conditions and actions necessary to exit
                            the error states and resume normal operation. The evaluator shall verify
                            that the TSS indicates these self-tests are run at start-up
                            automatically, and do not involve any inputs from or actions by the user
                            or operator. <h4>Guidance</h4> N/A <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall
                            perform the following tests: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall perform the integrity check on a known
                                    good TSF executable and verify that the check is
                                    successful.</test>
                                <test>The evaluator shall modify the TOE executable, performs the
                                    integrity check on the modified TSF executable and verify that
                                    the check fails.</test>
                                <test>The evaluator shall perform the integrity check on known good
                                    TOE data and verify that the check is successful.</test>
                                <test>the evaluator shall modify the TOE configuration data, perform
                                    the integrity check on the modified TOE data, and verify that
                                    the check fails.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
            </subsection>
            <subsection title="Class: Trusted Path/Channel (FTP)" id="trustedPath">
                <f-component id="FTP_ITC.1" name="Inter-TSF Trusted Channel">
                    <f-element id="FTP_ITC.1">
                        <title><b>Refinement:</b> The <!--                             
                                <selectables>
                                <selectable></selectable>
                                <selectable></selectable>
                            </selectables> --><selectables>
                                <selectable>TOE</selectable>
                                <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
                            </selectables> shall use <selectables>
                                <selectable>HTTPS</selectable>
                                <selectable>TLS</selectable>
                                <selectable>DTLS</selectable>
                            </selectables> to provide a trusted communication channel between itself
                            and another trusted IT product that is logically distinct from other
                            communication channels and provides assured identification of its end
                            points and protection of the channel data from disclosure and detection
                            of modification of the channel data.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FPT_ITC.1.2">
                        <title>The <selectables>
                                <selectable>TOE</selectable>
                                <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
                            </selectables> shall permit the TSF to initiate communication via the
                            trusted channel.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FPT_ITC.1.3">
                        <title>The <selectables>
                                <selectable>TOE</selectable>
                                <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
                            </selectables> shall initiate communication via the trusted channel for
                            all traffic traversing that connection.</title>
                        <note role="application"> The intent of the above requirement is to use the
                            cryptographic protocols identified in the requirement to establish and
                            maintain a trusted channel between the TOE and a trusted server. </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to determine that it
                            describes the details of the TOE connecting to a web server in terms of
                            the cryptographic protocols specified in the requirement, along with
                            TOE-specific options or procedures that might not be reflected in the
                            specification. The evaluator shall also confirm that all protocols
                            listed in the TSS are specified and included in the requirements in the
                            ST. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall confirm that the operational
                            guidance contains instructions for establishing the connection to the
                            access point, and that it contains recovery instructions should a
                            connection be unintentionally broken. <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall
                            perform the following tests: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall ensure that the TOE or TOE platform is
                                    able to initiate communications with a web server using the
                                    protocols specified in the requirement, setting up the
                                    connections as described in the operational guidance and
                                    ensuring that communication is successful.</test>
                                <test>The evaluator shall ensure, for each communication channel
                                    with a web server, the channel data is not sent in
                                    plaintext.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </chapter>

    <!--<chapter title="Security Assurance Requirements" id="sar"> The Security Objectives for the TOE
        in Section 3 were constructed to address threats identified in Section 2. The Security
        Functional Requirements (SFRs) in Section 4 are a formal instantiation of the Security
        Objectives. The EP draws from the <abbr linkend="CC"/> Security Assurance Requirements
        (SARs) to frame the extent to which the evaluator assesses the documentation applicable for
        the evaluation and performs independent testing.<br/> While this section contains the
        complete set of SARs from the <abbr linkend="CC"/>, the Assurance Activities to be performed
        by an evaluator are detailed both in Section 4 as well as in this section.<br/> The general
        model for evaluation of TOEs against STs written to conform to this EP is as follows:<br/>
        After the ST has been approved for evaluation, the Common Criteria Testing Laboratory (CCTL)
        will obtain access to a TOE and its supporting environmental IT, as well as its
        administrative guidance. The Assurance Activities listed in the ST (which will be refined by
        the CCTL to be TOE-specific, either within the ST or in a separate document) will then be
        performed by the CCTL. The results of these activities will be documented and presented
        (along with the administrative guidance used) for validation.<br/> For each family,
        “Developer Notes” are provided on the developer action elements to clarify what, if any,
        additional documentation/activity needs to be provided by the developer. For the
        content/presentation and evaluator activity elements, additional assurance activities are
        described as a whole for the family, rather than for each element. Additionally, the
        assurance activities described in this section are complementary to those specified in
        Section 4.<br/> The TOE security assurance requirements identify the management and
        evaluative activities required to address the threats identified in Section 4 of this EP. </chapter>
        -->
    <appendix id="opreq" title="Optional Requirements"> As indicated in the introduction to this EP,
        the baseline requirements (those that must be performed by the TOE or its underlying
        platform) are contained in the body of this EP. Additionally, there are three other types of
        requirements specified in Appendices B, C, and D.<br/> The first type (in this Appendix) are
        requirements that can be included in the ST, but do not have to be in order for a TOE to
        claim conformance to this EP. The second type (in Appendix C) are requirements based on
        selections in the body of the EP: if certain selections are made, then additional
        requirements in that appendix will need to be included. The third type (in Appendix D) are
        components that are not required in order to conform to this EP, but will be included in the
        baseline requirements in future versions of this EP. Note that the ST author is responsible
        for ensuring that requirements that may be associated with those in Appendix B, Appendix C,
        and/or Appendix D but are not listed (e.g., FMT-type requirements) are also included in the
        ST.<br/> At any time these may be included in the ST such that the TOE is still conformant
        to this EP. <section id="userdataprotection" title="Class: User Data Protection (FDP)">
            <f-component id="FDP_PBR_EXT.1" name="Extended: Private Browsing Sessions">
                <f-element id="FDP_PBR_EXT.1.1">
                    <title>The TOE shall provide the capability to support private browsing
                        sessions.</title>
                    <note role="application"> Private browsing is a mode that allows a user to
                        browse the web without storing data such as browsing history, images, and
                        cookies. Browsers that support this capability should include this
                        requirement. </note>
                    <aactivity>
                        <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it describes
                        how the TOE supports private browsing. The TSS shall specify the data that
                        is not stored locally when in private browsing mode and describe the
                        difference in interactions that the TOE has with websites when operating and
                        not operating in this mode. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine
                        the operational guidance to ensure it includes the steps for allowing or
                        disallowing private browsing <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall perform the
                        following test: <testlist>
                            <test>The evaluator shall clear the browsing history and cookie cache,
                                and shall and enable private browsing. The evaluator shall navigate
                                to test and/or actual websites and shall verify that the browsing
                                history and cookie cache remain unchanged</test>
                            <test>The evaluator shall disable private browsing and shall revisit the
                                same websites. The evaluator shall verify that the browsing history
                                and the cookie cache have been updated and reflect the evaluator‘s
                                browsing activities.</test>
                        </testlist>
                    </aactivity>
                </f-element>
            </f-component>
        </section>
    </appendix>
    <appendix id="selecationReqs" title="Selection-based Requirements">
        <!--Is text missing here?-->
        <section id="userData" title="Class: User Data Protection (FDP)">
            <f-component id="FDP_DEL_EXT.2" name="Extended: Deletion of Extension Information">
                <f-element id="FDP_DEL_EXT.2.1">
                    <title>The TOE shall provide the capability to delete extensions so that all
                        information is removed, including extensions, configuration elements, and
                        stored information.</title>
                    <aactivity>
                        <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it documents
                        where extensions are stored, where extensions are allowed to store
                        information. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the operational
                        guidance to verify that it includes instructions for how the user can delete
                        extensions. <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall perform the following tests: <testlist>
                            <test>The evaluator shall install a TOE extension, then examine the
                                TOE‘s file system to verify that the extension and extension data
                                are stored as documented. The evaluator shall then uninstall the TOE
                                extension and examine the TOE‘s file system to verify that the
                                extension and extension data are removed from the documented
                                locations.</test>
                        </testlist>
                    </aactivity>
                </f-element>
            </f-component>
            <f-component id="FDP_DEL_EXT.3" name="Extended: Deletion of Plug-in Information">
                <f-element id="FDP_DEL_EXT.3.1">
                    <title>The TOE shall provide the capability to delete plug-ins so that all
                        information is removed, including plug-ins, configuration elements, and
                        stored information.</title>
                    <aactivity>
                        <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it documents
                        where plug-ins are stored, where plug-ins are allowed to store information,
                        and whether the option exists to delete all plug-in information.
                            <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the operational guidance
                        to verify that it includes instructions for how the user can delete plug-ins
                        and associated content. <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall perform the
                        following tests: <testlist>
                            <test>The evaluator shall install a TOE plug-in, then examine the TOE‘s
                                file system to verify that the plug-in and plug-in data are stored
                                as documented. The evaluator shall then uninstall the TOE plug-in
                                and examine the TOE‘s file system to verify that the plug-in and
                                plug-in data are removed from the documented locations.</test>
                        </testlist>
                    </aactivity>
                </f-element>
            </f-component>
        </section>
        <section id="tsfProtection" title="Class: Protection of the TSF (FPT)">
            <f-component id="FPT_TUD_EXT.2" name="Extended: Trusted Extension Update">
                <f-element id="FPT_TUD_EXT.2.1">
                    <title>The TOE shall provide the capability to query the current version of the
                        extension.</title>
                </f-element>
                <f-element id="FPT_TUD_EXT.2.2">
                    <title>The TOE shall provide the capability to initiate extension
                        updates.</title>
                </f-element>
                <f-element id="FTP_TUD_EXT.2.3">
                    <title>The TOE shall provide a means to verify extensions and extension updates
                        using a digital signature mechanism prior to installing the extension or
                        extension updates.</title>
                </f-element>
                <f-element id="FTP_TUD_EXT.2.4">
                    <title>The TOE shall prevent websites from automatically installing
                        extensions.</title>
                    <note role="application"> Extensions are bundles of code that are added to the
                        browser to add specific functionality that the browser does not provide by
                        default. Extensions could be developed by the browser vendor or by third
                        parties and are allowed full access to view and interact with the web
                        content that the browser sees. Extensions are common on non-mobile
                        platforms, but may not be supported on mobile platforms, where HTML5 tends
                        to be used for websites that serve rich content. </note>
                    <aactivity>
                        <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify that it describes
                        the ability of the TSF to verify that extensions and extension updates come
                        from a trusted source. The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify that it
                        states that the TSF will reject extensions from unapproved sources.
                            <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the operational guidance
                        to verify that it includes instructions on how to configure the TOE with
                        trusted extension sources. <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator shall perform the
                        following tests: <testlist>
                            <test>The evaluator shall configure the TOE with trusted sources. The
                                evaluator shall create or obtain an extension signed by a trusted
                                source and attempt to install it. The evaluator shall verify that
                                the signature on the extension is valid.</test>
                            <test>The evaluator shall create or obtain an extension signed by an
                                untrusted source and attempt to install it. The evaluator shall
                                verify that the signed extension is rejected.</test>
                            <test>The evaluator shall create or obtain an extension signed with an
                                invalid certificate and attempt to install it. The evaluator shall
                                verify that the signed extension is rejected.</test>
                            <test>The evaluator shall create or obtain an extension signed by a
                                trusted source, modify the extension without re-signing it, and
                                attempt to install it. The evaluator shall verify that the signed
                                extension is rejected.</test>
                        </testlist>
                    </aactivity>
                </f-element>
            </f-component>
            <f-component id="FPT_TUD_EXT.3" name="Extended: Trusted Plug-in Update">
                <f-element id="FPT_TUD_EXT.3.1">
                    <title>The TOE shall provide the ability to query the current version of the
                        plug-in.</title>
                </f-element>
                <f-element id="FPT_TUD_EXT.3.2">
                    <title>The TOE shall provide the ability to initiate the downloading of plug-ins
                        and plug-in updates.</title>
                </f-element>
                <f-element id="FTP_TUD_EXT.3.3">
                    <title>The TOE shall provide a means to verify plug-ins using a digital
                        signature mechanism and <selectables>
                            <selectable>published hash</selectable>
                            <selectable>no other functions</selectable>
                        </selectables> prior to installing the plug-in.</title>
                </f-element>
                <f-element id="FTP_TUD_EXT.3.4">
                    <title>The TOE shall prevent websites from automatically installing
                        plug-ins.</title>
                    <aactivity>
                        <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify that it states
                        that the TSF will reject plug-ins from unapproved sources. <h4>Guidance</h4>
                        The evaluator shall examine the operational guidance to verify that it
                        includes instructions on how to configure the TOE with trusted plug-in
                        sources. <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator shall perform the following tests: <testlist>
                            <test>The evaluator shall configure the TOE with trusted plug-in
                                sources. The evaluator shall create or obtain a plug-in signed by a
                                trusted source and attempt to install it. The evaluator shall verify
                                that the signature on the plug-in is valid.</test>
                            <test>The evaluator shall create or obtain a plug-in signed by an
                                untrusted source and attempt to install it. The evaluator shall
                                verify that the signed plug-in is rejected.</test>
                            <test>The evaluator shall create or obtain a plug-in signed with an
                                invalid certificate and attempt to install it. The evaluator shall
                                verify that the signed plug-in is valid.</test>
                            <test>The evaluator shall create or obtain a plug-in signed by a trusted
                                source, modify the plug-in without re-signing it, and attempt to
                                install it. The evaluator shall verify that the signed plug-in is
                                rejected.</test>
                        </testlist>
                    </aactivity>
                </f-element>
            </f-component>
        </section>
    </appendix>
    <appendix id="objReqs" title="Objective Requirements"> As indicated in the introduction to this
        EP, the baseline requirements (those that must be performed by the TOE or its underlying
        platform) are contained in the body of this EP. There are additional requirements that
        specify security functionality that is desirable and these requirements are contained in
        this Annex. It is expected that these requirements will transition from objective
        requirements to baseline requirements in future versions of this EP. 
        <section id="audit" title="Class: Security Audit (FAU)">
            <f-component id="FAU_GEN.1" name="Audit Data Generation">
                <f-element id="FAU_GEN.1.1">
                    <title>The <selectables>
                            <selectable>TOE</selectable>
                            <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
                        </selectables> shall be able to generate an audit record of the following
                        auditable events: <ul>
                            <li>Start-up and shutdown of the audit functions;</li>
                            <li>All auditable events for the not specified level of audit;</li>
                            <li><i>Specifically defined auditable events listed in Table
                                5].</i></li>
                        </ul>
                    </title>
                </f-element>
                <f-element id="FAU_GEN.1.2">
                    <title>The <selectables>
                            <selectable>TOE</selectable>
                            <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
                        </selectables> shall record within each audit record at least the following
                        information: <ul>
                            <li>Date and time of the event, type of event, subject identity, and the
                                outcome (success or failure) of the event.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </title>
                    <note role="application"> The ST author can include other auditable events
                        directly in the table; they are not limited to the list presented. </note>
                    <aactivity>
                        <h4>TSS</h4> N/A <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the
                        operational guidance to ensure that it lists all of the auditable events and
                        provides a format for audit records. Each audit record format type must be
                        covered, along with a brief description of each field. The evaluator shall
                        ensure that the TSS describes every audit event type mandated by the EP and
                        that the description of the fields contains the information required in
                        FAU_GEN.1.2. <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator shall test the TOE‘s ability to
                        correctly generate audit records by having the TOE generate audit records
                        for the events listed in FAU_GEN.1.1. This should include all instances of
                        an event. The evaluator shall test that audit records are generated for the
                        establishment and termination of a channel for each of the cryptographic
                        protocols contained in the ST. For administrative actions, the evaluator
                        shall test that each action determined by the evaluator above to be security
                        relevant in the context of this EP is auditable. When verifying the test
                        results, the evaluator shall ensure the audit records generated during
                        testing match the format specified in the operational guidance, and that the
                        fields in each audit record have the proper entries and that the audit
                        records are provided in a manner suitable for interpretation. The evaluator
                        shall also ensure the ability to apply searches of audit data based on the
                        type of event, the user responsible for causing the event, and identity of
                        the applicable certificate.<br/> Note that the testing here can be
                        accomplished in conjunction with the testing of the security mechanisms
                        directly. For example, testing performed to ensure that the operational
                        guidance provided is correct verifies that AGD_OPE.1 is satisfied and should
                        address the invocation of the administrative actions that are needed to
                        verify the audit records are generated as expected.<br/>
                        <table>
                            <tr class="header"><TH colspan="3">Table 5. Auditable Events</TH>
                            </tr>
                            <tr><th>Requirement</th><th>Auditable Events</th><th>Additional Audit
                                    Record Contents</th></tr>
                            <TR><TD>FAU_GEN.1</TD><TD>None.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FAU_SEL.1</TD><TD>All modifications to the audit configuration
                                    that occur while the audit collection functions are
                                    operating.</TD>
                                <TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FCS_CKM.1(*)</TD><TD>Failure of the key generation
                                    activity.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FCS_CKM_EXT.1</TD><TD>None.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FCS_CKM_EXT.4</TD><TD>Failure of the key zeroization
                                    process.</TD><TD>Identity of object or entity being
                                    cleared.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FCS_COP.1(1)</TD><TD>Failure of encryption or
                                    decryption.</TD><TD>Cryptographic mode of operation,
                                    name/identifier of object being encrypted/decrypted.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FCS_COP.1(2)</TD><TD>Failure of hashing
                                    function.</TD><TD>Cryptographic mode of operation,
                                    name/identifier of object being hashed.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FCS_COP.1(3)</TD><TD>Failure of cryptographic
                                    signature.</TD><TD>Cryptographic mode of operation,
                                    name/identifier of object being signed/verified.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FCS_COP.1(4)</TD><TD>Failure in cryptographic hashing for
                                    non-data integrity.</TD><TD>Cryptographic mode of operation,
                                    name/identifier of object being hashed.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FCS_DTLS_EXT.1</TD><TD>Failure to establish a DTLS
                                    session.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FCS_HTTPS_EXT.1</TD><TD>Failure to establish a HTTPS
                                    session</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FCS_RBG_EXT.1</TD><TD>Failure of the randomization
                                    process.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FCS_STS_EXT.1</TD><TD>None.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FCS_TLSC_EXT.1</TD><TD>Failure to establish a TLS
                                    session.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FDP_ACC_EXT.1</TD><TD>None.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FDP_ACF_EXT.1</TD><TD>None.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FDP_COO_EXT.1</TD><TD>Failure to block third party
                                    cookies.</TD><TD>None</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FDP_CSP_EXT.1</TD><TD>None</TD><TD>None</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FDP_DEL_EXT.1</TD><TD>None</TD><TD>None</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FDP_DEL_EXT.2</TD><TD>None</TD><TD>None</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FDP_DEL_EXT.3</TD><TD>None</TD><TD>None</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FDP_PBR_EXT.1</TD><TD>None</TD><TD>None</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FDP_PST_EXT.1</TD><TD>None</TD><TD>None</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FDP_SBX_EXT.1</TD><TD>All violations of process
                                    restrictions.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FDP_SOP_EXT.1</TD><TD>All exceptions to Same Origin
                                    Policy.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FDP_STR_EXT.1</TD><TD>None.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FDP_TRK_EXT.1</TD><TD>None.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FIA_X509_EXT.1</TD><TD>Failure of the X.509 certificate
                                    validation.</TD><TD>Reason for failure of validation.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FIA_X509_EXT.2</TD><TD>None.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FMT_MOF.1</TD><TD>Any security-relevant changes to the
                                    configuration of the TOE.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FMT_SMF.1</TD><TD>None.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FMT_SMR.1</TD><TD>None.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FPT_DNL_EXT.1</TD><TD>None.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FPT_DNL_EXT.2</TD><TD>None.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FPT_INT_EXT.1</TD><TD>None.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FPT_INT_EXT.2</TD><TD>None.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FPT_INT_EXT.3</TD><TD>None.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FPT_MCD_EXT.1</TD><TD>All instances of running unsigned mobile
                                    code. All instances of running mobile code from an untrusted or
                                    unverified source.</TD><TD>Certificate subject</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FPT_TST_EXT.1</TD><TD>Execution of this set of TSF self-tests.
                                    Detected integrity violations.</TD><TD>For integrity violations,
                                    the TSF code file that caused the integrity violation.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FPT_TUD_EXT.1</TD><TD>Initiation of the update. Any failure to
                                    verify the integrity of the update.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FPT_TUD_EXT.2</TD><TD>Initiation of the update. Any failure to
                                    verify the integrity of the update.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FPT_TUD_EXT.3</TD><TD>Initiation of the update. Any failure to
                                    verify the integrity of the update.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                            <TR><TD>FTP_ITC.1</TD><TD>All attempts to establish a trusted channel.
                                    Detection of modification of channel
                                data.</TD><TD>None.</TD></TR>
                        </table>
                    </aactivity>
                </f-element>
            </f-component>
            <f-component id="FAU_SEL.1" name="Selective Audit">
                <f-element id="FAU_SEL.1.1">
                    <title>The <selectables>
                            <selectable>TOE</selectable>
                            <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
                        </selectables> shall be able to select the set of events to be audited from
                        the set of all auditable events based on the following attributes: <ol><!-- HERE these have letters in the published version -->
                            <li>event type;</li>
                            <li>success of auditable security events;</li>
                            <li>failure of auditable security events; and</li>
                            <li>[assignment: other attributes].</li>
                        </ol></title>
                    <note role="application"> The intent of this requirement is to identify all
                        criteria that can be selected to trigger an audit event. This can be
                        configured through an interface on the client for a user/administrator to
                        invoke. For the ST author, the assignment is used to list any additional
                        criteria or ―none‖. The auditable event types are listed in Table 5. </note>
                    <aactivity>
                        <h4>TSS</h4> N/A <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the
                        operational guidance to ensure that the guidance itemizes all event types,
                        as well as describes all attributes that are to be selectable in accordance
                        with the requirement, to include those attributes listed in the assignment.
                        The operational guidance shall also identify those audit records that are
                        always recorded, regardless of the selection criteria currently being
                        enforced. <h4>Tests</h4> The testing should be accomplished in conjunction
                        with the testing of FAU_GEN.1.1. </aactivity>
                </f-element>
            </f-component>
        </section>
        <section id="cryptoSupportClass" title="Class: Cryptographic Support (FCS)">
            <f-component id="FCS_STS_EXT.1" name="Extended: Strict Transport Security">
                <f-element id="FCS_STS_EXT.1.1">
                    <title>The <selectables>
                            <selectable>TOE</selectable>
                            <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
                        </selectables> shall implement HTTP Strict-Transport-Security according to
                        RFC 6797</title>
                </f-element>
                <f-element id="FCS_STS_EXT.1.2">
                    <title>The <selectables>
                            <selectable>TOE</selectable>
                            <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
                        </selectables> shall retain persistent data signaling HSTS enablement for
                        the time span declared by the website in a max-age directive.</title>
                </f-element>
                <f-element id="FCS_STS_EXT.1.3">
                    <title>The <selectables>
                            <selectable>TOE</selectable>
                            <selectable>TOE platform</selectable>
                        </selectables> shall cache the freshest Strict Security policy
                        information.</title>
                    <note role="application"> If a browser receives the HSTS header from a website,
                        all future HTTP sessions between the TOE and the domain or superdomain of
                        that website must occur over TLS 1.2 (RFC 5246) or greater by utilizing
                        HTTPS (RFC 2818). </note>
                    <aactivity>
                        <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it documents
                        how the TOE supports HSTS. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the
                        operational guidance to ensure it contains instructions on how to use HSTS.
                            <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator shall perform the following tests: <testlist>
                            <test>The evaluator shall connect to a HSTS-compliant website while
                                running a network protocol analyzer to monitor the traffic. The
                                evaluator shall examine the captured network traffic and verify that
                                a Strict Transport Security header is received and that there is a
                                directive for the max-age of the HSTS relationship.</test>
                            <test>The evaluator shall reconnect to the HSTS website again over HTTP
                                and shall verify that the session is redirected to HTTPS.</test>
                            <test>The evaluator shall reconnect to the HSTS website after the
                                max-age has expired, and verify that the website and TOE reestablish
                                an HSTS relationship.</test>
                            <test>The evaluator shall update the website HSTS information, and
                                verify that when the TOE reconnects to the website, that information
                                is updated by the TOE.</test>
                        </testlist>
                    </aactivity>
                </f-element>
            </f-component>
        </section>
        <section id="objuserDataProtection" title="Class: User Data Protection (FDP)">
            <f-component id="FDP_ACC_EXT.1" name="Extended: Access Control on Domains">
                <f-element id="FDP_ACC_EXT.1.1">
                    <title>The TOE shall provide the capability to group domains and apply access
                        restrictions to specific sets of domains.</title>
                    <note role="application"> An example of this functionality is the concept of
                        zones in Internet Explorer. </note>
                    <aactivity>
                        <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes how
                        the TSF supports the grouping of domains and applying access restrictions to
                        them. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the operational guidance
                        to ensure it documents the steps for configuring the ability to group
                        domains and apply access restrictions. <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator shall
                        perform the following tests: <ul>
                            <li>The evaluator shall create a group of domains and apply a specific
                                restriction to the group. The evaluator shall navigate to websites
                                within the domains in the restricted group and shall verify that the
                                restriction is functional. The evaluator shall navigate to websites
                                within domains not in the restricted group and shall verify that the
                                restriction does not apply.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </aactivity>
                </f-element>
            </f-component>
            <f-component id="FDP_PST_EXT.1" name="Extended: Storage of Persistent Information">
                <f-element id="FDP_PST_EXT.1.1">
                    <title>The TOE shall provide the capability to operate without storing
                        persistent data to the file system.</title>
                    <note role="application"> Exceptions from this requirement are credentials and
                        configuration information. </note>
                    <aactivity>
                        <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify it describes how
                        the TOE operates without storing persistent user data to the file systems.
                            <h4>Guidance</h4> N/A <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator shall perform the
                        following test: <testlist>
                            <test>The evaluator shall operate the TOE for a period of time, ensuring
                                that a wide variety of TOE functionality has been exercised. The
                                evaluator shall then examine the TOE and the underlying platform to
                                ensure that no files have been written to the file system other than
                                credentials or configuration information.</test>
                        </testlist>
                    </aactivity>
                </f-element>
            </f-component>
        </section>
        <section id="objTsfProtection" title="Class: Protection of the TSF (FPT)">
            <f-component id="FPT_INT_EXT.2"
                name="Extended: Interactions with Application Reputation Services">
                <f-element id="FPT_INT_EXT.2.1">
                    <title>The TOE shall utilize an application reputation service to prevent
                        downloading of malicious applications.</title>
                    <note role="application"> An application reputation service is an online service
                        that identifies malicious applications; it is used to detect such
                        applications prior to downloading them. </note>
                    <aactivity>
                        <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes the
                        TOE‘s use of application reputation services in detecting malicious
                        applications. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the operational
                        guidance to ensure it describes the TOE‘s support for use of an application
                        reputation service, including which services the TOE supports by default (if
                        any) and whether additional services can be configured. The operational
                        guidance shall include steps for how to configure the application reputation
                        service. <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator shall perform the following tests: <testlist>
                            <test>The evaluator shall configure the TOE to enable the use of one or
                                more application reputation services per the operational guidance.
                                The evaluator shall initiate a connection with a website that
                                attempts to download an application to the TOE while sniffing the
                                network traffic using a network protocol analyzer. The evaluator
                                shall inspect the captured network traffic and shall verify that the
                                TOE initiates a connection to the configured application reputation
                                service(s) before initiating the download.</test>
                        </testlist>
                    </aactivity>
                </f-element>
            </f-component>
            <f-component id="FPT_INT_EXT.3"
                name="Extended: Interactions with URL Reputation Services">
                <f-element id="FPT_INT_EXT.3.1">
                    <title>The TOE shall utilize a URL reputation service to prevent connections
                        with malicious websites.</title>
                    <note role="application"> A URL reputation service is an online service that
                        identifies websites with malicious or phishing content applications; it is
                        used to detect such websites prior to allowing users to access them. The
                        goal of this requirement is to ensure that the TOE is prevented from
                        establishing connections with known-bad sources of malware on the Internet.
                        The specifics of the sequence of actions taken before a block decision is
                        made may depend upon the specific implementation of the TOE. For example,
                        some TOEs might implement the check for malicious content by checking
                        against the list of bad URLs provided by the URL reputation service in real
                        time; others may download updated lists of bad URLs at TOE startup, updating
                        the list periodically from the URL reputation service(s) until the TOE is
                        terminated. Ultimately, the result should be that the TOE blocks the
                        connection to the bad URL. </note>
                    <aactivity>
                        <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes the
                        TSF‘s use of a URL reputation service in detecting malicious websites.
                            <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the operational guidance
                        to ensure it describes the TOE‘s support for use of URL reputation services,
                        including which services the TOE supports by default (if any) and whether
                        additional services can be configured. The operational guidance shall
                        include steps for how to configure the URL reputation service.
                            <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator shall perform the following tests: <testlist>
                            <test>The evaluator shall configure the TOE to enable the use of one or
                                more URL reputation services per the operational guidance. The
                                evaluator shall initiate a connection with a known good website
                                while sniffing the network traffic using a network protocol
                                analyzer. The evaluator shall inspect the captured network traffic
                                and shall verify that the TOE initiates a connection to the
                                configured URL reputation service(s).</test>
                            <test>The evaluator shall configure the TOE to enable the use of one or
                                more URL reputation services per the operational guidance. The
                                evaluator shall initiate a connection with a known malicious website
                                that is identified by one or more of the URL reputation services
                                while sniffing the network traffic using a network protocol
                                analyzer. The evaluator shall verify that a warning appears alerting
                                that the website is known to be malicious and the TOE is not allowed
                                to connect. The evaluator shall inspect the captured network traffic
                                and shall verify that the TOE initiates a connection to the
                                configured URL reputation service(s) and retrieved an updated list
                                of malicious URLs with the tested website being on the list.</test>
                        </testlist>
                    </aactivity>
                </f-element>
            </f-component>
        </section>
    </appendix>
   

        <appendix id="biblio" title="References">
            <section id="ref">
                <description xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/cc">Common Criteria
                    for Information Technology Security Evaluation <ul>
                        <li><a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART1V3.1R4.pdf"
                            >Part 1: Introduction and General Model</a>, CCMB-2012-09-001,
                            Version 3.1 Revision 4, September 2012.</li>
                        <li><a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART2V3.1R4.pdf"
                            >Part 2: Security Functional Components</a>, CCMB-2012-09-002,
                            Version 3.1 Revision 4, September 2012.</li>
                        <li><a href="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/application/output/application.html">
                            Protection Profile for Application Software</a>, Version 1.1,
                                    2014-11-05. </li>
                </ul>
                </description>      
            </section>
        </appendix>

    <appendix title="Acronyms" id="acronyms">
            <acronyms>
                <entry>
                    <term>AES</term>
                    <description>Advanced Encryption Standard</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>CBC</term>
                    <description>Cipher Block Chaining</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>CRL</term>
                    <description>Certificate Revocation List</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>CSP</term>
                    <description>Cryptographic Service Provider</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>CSRF</term>
                    <description>Cross Site Request Forgery</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>DHE</term>
                    <description>Diffie-Hellman Key Exchange</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>DN</term>
                    <description>Distinguished Name</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>DSA</term>
                    <description>Digital Signature Algorithm</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>DTLS</term>
                    <description>Datagram Transport Layer Security</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>ECC</term>
                    <description>Elliptic Curve Cryptography</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>ECDSA</term>
                    <description>Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>EP</term>
                    <description>Extended Package</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>FFC</term>
                    <description>Finite-Field Cryptography</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>FIPS</term>
                    <description>Federal Information Processing Standards</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>GCM</term>
                    <description>Galois/Counter Mode</description>
                </entry>
                <TR>
                    <term>GPU</term>
                    <description>Graphics Processing Unit</description>
                </TR>
                <entry>
                    <term>HMAC</term>
                    <description>Keyed Hash Message Authentication Code</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>HTML</term>
                    <description>HyperText Markup Language</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>HTML5</term>
                    <description>HyperText Markup Language version 5</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>HTTP</term>
                    <description>HyperText Transfer Protocol</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>HTTPS</term>
                    <description>HyperText Transfer Protocol Secure</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>IETF</term>
                    <description>Internet Engineering Task Force</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>IV</term>
                    <description>Initialization Vector</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>KAT</term>
                    <description>Known Answer Test</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>KDF</term>
                    <description>Key Derivation Function</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>NIST</term>
                    <description>National Institute of Standards and Technology</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>OCSP</term>
                    <description>Online Certificate Status Protocol</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>OID</term>
                    <description>Object Identifier</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>PDF</term>
                    <description>Portable Document Format</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>rDSA</term>
                    <description>RSA Digital Signature Algorithm</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>RFC</term>
                    <description>Request for Comment (IETF)</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>RGB</term>
                    <description>Random Bit Generator</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>RSA</term>
                    <description>Rivest Shamir Adelman</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>SaaS</term>
                    <description>Software as a Service</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>SHA</term>
                    <description>Secure Hash Algorithm</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>SSL</term>
                    <description>Secure Sockets Layer</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>TLS</term>
                    <description>Transport Layer Security</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>W3C</term>
                    <description>World Wide Web Consortium</description>
                </entry>
                <entry>
                    <term>XSS</term>
                    <description>Cross Site Scripting</description>
                </entry>
        </acronyms>
    </appendix>
    
    <!-- 
                <h4></h4>
                <f-component id="" name="">
                    <f-element id="">
                        <title></title>
                        <note role="application">
                            
                        </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4>
                            
                            <h4>Guidance</h4>
                            
                            <h4>Tests</h4>
                            <ul>
                                <li></li>
                            </ul>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
    -->
    <!--              
            <selectables linebreak="yes">
                <selectable> </selectable>
                <selectable> </selectable>
                <selectable>  </selectable>
              </selectables>
        -->
    <!-- 
                            <selectables linebreak="yes">
                                <selectable><li></li></selectable>
                                <selectable><li></li></selectable>
                            </selectables>
        -->
    <!-- 
              <TR class="header">
        <TH colspan="2">Table 3: Security Threats to Objectives Mapping</TH>
      </TR>
      <TR>
        <TH>Threat</TH>
        <TH>Objective</TH>
      </TR>
      -->
</PP>
