<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/pp2html.xsl"?>
<PP xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/cc" name="Web Browsers">
    <PPReference title="PP Reference" id="ID003">
        <ReferenceTable>
            <PPTitle>Application Software Extended Package for Web Browsers</PPTitle>
            <PPVersion>Draft 1.9</PPVersion>
            <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
            <PPPubDate>2015-04-08</PPPubDate>
            <PPCertificationID>unassigned</PPCertificationID>
            <CCVersion>Version 3.1</CCVersion>
            <Keywords>web browser; browser</Keywords>
            <entry>
                <name>Registration</name>
                <description>National Information Assurance Partnership</description>
            </entry>
        </ReferenceTable>
    </PPReference>
    <RevisionHistory role="draft">
        <entry>
            <version>v 1.0</version>
            <date>2014-03-31</date>
            <subject>Release - Protection Profile for Web Browsers</subject>
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <version>v 1.9</version>
            <date>2014-12-04</date>
            <subject>Interim Draft - Update as Extended Package of the Protection Profile for
                Application Software</subject>
        </entry>
    </RevisionHistory>
    <RevisionHistory role="release">
        <entry>
            <version>v 1.0</version>
            <date>2014-03-31</date>
            <subject>Initial release as Protection Profile for Web Browsers</subject>
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <version>v 2.0</version>
            <date>2014-12-12</date>
            <subject>Update as Extended Package of the Protection Profile for Application
                Software</subject>
        </entry>
    </RevisionHistory>
    <chapter title="Introduction" id="int">
        <section title="Overview" id="ppoverview">The scope of this Extended Package (EP) is to
            describe the security functionality of web browsers in terms of <cite linkend="bibCC"/>.
            This EP is not complete in itself, but rather extends the security requirements of the
            Protection Profile for Application Software (<cite linkend="bibAppPP"/>). </section>
        <section title="Terms" id="glossary">The following sections provide both Common Criteria and
            technology terms used in this Extended Package. <subsection
                title="Common Criteria Terms" id="ccterms">
                <glossary>
                    <entry>
                        <term><abbr title="Common Criteria">CC</abbr></term>
                        <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security
                            Evaluation.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term><abbr title="Extended Package">EP</abbr></term>
                        <description>An implementation-independent set of security requirements for
                            a category of products, which extends those in a Protection
                            Profile.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term><abbr title="Protection Profile">PP</abbr></term>
                        <description>An implementation-independent set of security requirements for
                            a category of products.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term><abbr title="Security Target">ST</abbr></term>
                        <description>A set of implementation-dependent security requirements for a
                            specific product.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term><abbr title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</abbr></term>
                        <description>The product under evaluation. In this case, application
                            software and its supporting documentation.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term><abbr title="TOE Security Functionality">TSF</abbr></term>
                        <description>The security functionality of the product under
                            evaluation.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term><abbr title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</abbr></term>
                        <description>A description of how a <abbr linkend="TOE"/> satisfies the SFRs
                            in a <abbr linkend="ST"/>. </description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term><abbr title="Security Functional Requirement">SFR</abbr></term>
                        <description>A requirement for security enforcement by the <abbr
                                linkend="TOE"/>. </description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term><abbr title="Security Assurance Requirement">SAR</abbr></term>
                        <description>A requirement to assure the security of the <abbr linkend="TOE"
                            />. </description>
                    </entry>
                </glossary>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="techterms" title="Technology Terms">
                <glossary>
                    <entry>
                        <term>Add-on</term>
                        <description>Capabilities or functionality added to an application. This
                            term includes plug-ins, extensions, and other controls.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>Administrator</term>
                        <description>The Administrator is responsible for management activities,
                            including setting the policy that is applied by the enterprise on the
                            Browser. This administrator is likely to be acting remotely. If the
                            platform is unmanaged by an enterprise, the user can act as the
                            administrator.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>CSRF</term>
                        <description>Cross Site Request Forgery - Vulnerability where an attacker
                            gets a target user to execute a script with that user's
                            privileges.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>Domain</term>
                        <description>A realm of administrative autonomy, authority or control on the
                            Internet (e.g., cnn.com).</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>Extension</term>
                        <description>Bundle of code added to the browser to add specific
                            functionality that the browser does not provide by
                            default.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>HTML</term>
                        <description>HyperText Markup Language - Language used by web servers to
                            present content to browsers.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>HTML5</term>
                        <description>HyperText Markup Language version 5, a new version of HTML that
                            incorporates many new features that enrich the browsing
                            experience.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>HTTP</term>
                        <description>HyperText Transfer Protocol - Protocol for communicating on the
                            web.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>HTTPS</term>
                        <description>HyperText Transfer Protocol Secure; secure version of HTTP that
                            runs over an encrypted channel (SSL/TLS).</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>JavaScript</term>
                        <description>Scripting language commonly integrated into web pages to
                            generate dynamic, interactive content.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>Mobile Code</term>
                        <description>Software transmitted from a remote system for execution within
                            a limited execution environment on the local system. Typically, there is
                            no persistent installation and execution begins without the user's
                            consent or even notification. Examples of mobile code technologies
                            include Java applets, Adobe ActionScript, and Microsoft Silverlight. <br/>
                            <b>Note:</b> JavaScript is not included in references to mobile code in
                            this browser EP.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>Plug-in</term>
                        <description>Browser add-on to handle specific types of web
                            content.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>Pop-up</term>
                        <description>Piece of web code that causes a browser to open
                            a window outside the window that is currently in focus.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>Port</term>
                        <description>An application-specific construct that functions as a
                            communications endpoint in a computer's host OS; in a web environment,
                            port 80 is the default port for HTTP communications, although other
                            ports can be used. In a web address, the port follows the domain or
                            sub-domain name (e.g., http://www.cnn.com:80).</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>Protocol</term>
                        <description>A system of digital rules for data exchange within or between
                            computers; in a web environment, the typical protocols are HTTP and
                            HTTPS.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>Sandbox</term>
                        <description>Security mechanism for separating running processes, most often
                            used to run untrusted or vulnerable processes by reducing their
                            privileges to such an extent that they should not be able to harm the
                            host system.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>Sensitive Data</term>
                        <description>Sensitive data may include all user or enterprise data or may
                            be specific application data such as emails, messaging, documents,
                            calendar items, and contacts. Sensitive data must minimally include PII,
                            credentials, and keys. Sensitive data shall be identified in the
                            application's TSS by the ST author.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>Sub-domain</term>
                        <description>An Internet domain which is part of a primary domain, donated
                            by a prefix before the primary domain (e.g.,
                            news.cnn.com).</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>Tabs</term>
                        <description>Allow the browsers to display content from multiple web sites
                            in the same window.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>Web Browser</term>
                        <description>Application that retrieves and renders content provided by a
                            web server. The terms web browser, browser, and TOE are interchangeable
                            in this document.</description>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <term>XSS</term>
                        <description>Cross Site Scripting - Injection of untrusted content into a
                            vulnerable web application to render or execute that content on a
                            victim's system.</description>
                    </entry>
                </glossary>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation" id="TOEdescription"> This document provides
            an extended set of Security Functional Requirements (SFRs) for a web browser, which is
            the Target of Evaluation (TOE). The terms web browser, browser, and TOE are
            interchangeable in this document.<br/> The Protection Profile for Application Software
            defines the baseline SFRs for application software which runs on mobile devices ("apps")
            as well as on desktop and server platforms. This Extended Package (EP) for web browsers
            is not complete in itself, but rather extends the Protection Profile for Application
            Software. <br/> Web browsers are client applications that retrieve and render content
            provided by web servers, primarily using the HyperText Transfer Protocol (HTTP) or HTTP
            Secure (HTTPS). Browsers have grown in complexity over the years, starting as tools used
            to display simple, static web pages and becoming sophisticated execution environments
            for rich web content. The use of browsers to administer accounts, servers or embedded
            systems remotely requires them to handle sensitive information securely. Innovations
            such as tabs, extensions and HTML5 have not only increased browser functionality, but
            also introduced new security concerns. As users' principal method for accessing the
            Internet, and due to their complexity and the information that they process, browsers
            are a natural target for attackers. As a result, it is paramount that the security of
            web browsers be assured to reduce the risk to networks.</section>
        <section title="Use Cases" id="usecases"> Web browsers are used to perform many tasks, and
            these can be categorized into three primary use cases.<usecases>
                <usecase title="Surfing the Web">
                    <description> Browsers are used to retrieve, display and render content from the
                        web, such as web pages, streaming media, images and specialized formats
                        (e.g., Java, Flash, PDF). They can also be used to write content to web
                        sites (web 2.0 – e.g., Facebook). Web surfing can be done over the Internet
                        or within an Intranet.</description>
                </usecase>
                <usecase title="Remote Administration Client">
                    <description> Browsers are used to provide remote administration interfaces for
                        systems such as servers, network devices and embedded systems, to include
                        supervisory control and data acquisition (SCADA) systems, smart TVs and
                        thermostats. As opposed to surfing the web, where the browser may be
                        interacting with untrusted content, the browser, acting as a Remote
                        Administration Client, is connecting to a server that the user
                        trusts.</description>
                </usecase>
                <usecase title="Content Creation">
                    <description> Browsers are used to create content via an increasing number of
                        Software as a Service (SaaS) offerings, including Microsoft Office 365,
                        Google Drive, and Adobe Creative Cloud, where user data and records are
                        stored online.</description>
                </usecase>
            </usecases>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter title="Conformance Claims" id="conf">
        <cclaims>
            <cclaim id="Conformance Statement">
                <description> The Protection Profile for Application Software (App PP) defines the
                    baseline Security Functional Requirements (SFRs) and Security Assurance
                    Requirements (SARs) for application software products. This EP serves to extend
                    the App PP baseline with additional SFRs and associated Assurance Activities
                    specific to a web browser. Assurance Activities are the actions that the
                    evaluator performs in order to determine a web browser's compliance to the
                    SFRs.<br/> This EP conforms to Common Criteria <cite linkend="bibCC"/> for
                    Information Technology Security Evaluation, Version 3.1, Revision 4. It is CC
                    Part 2 extended and CC Part 3 conformant. In order to be conformant to this EP,
                    the ST must include all components in this EP and the associated App PP that
                    are: <ul><li>unconditional (which are always required)</li>
                        <li>selection-based (which are required when certain selections are chosen
                            in the unconditional requirements)</li></ul> and may include optional
                    and/or objective components that are desirable but not required for conformance.
                </description>
            </cclaim>
        </cclaims>
    </chapter>
    <chapter title="Security Problem Description" id="spd"> The security problem is described in
        terms of the threats that the web browser is expected to address, assumptions about the
        operational environment, and any organizational security policies that it is expected to
        enforce. <br/> This Extended Package does not repeat the threats, assumptions, and
        organizational security policies identified in the App PP, though they all apply given the
        conformance and hence dependence of this EP on it. Together the threats, assumptions and
        organizational security policies of the App PP and those defined in this EP describe those
        addressed by a web browser as the Target of Evaluation. <br/> Notably, browsers are
        particularly at risk from the Network Attack threat identified in the App PP. Attackers can
        use phishing or another social engineering technique to persuade a user to visit a malicious
        site. Users may also unintentionally visit malicious sites in the course of web browsing.
        Such sites then present malicious content to the user's browser to exploit it and perform
        installation of malware, often with no indication to the user. <section title="Threats"
            id="threattable">The following threats are specific to web browsers, and represent an
            addition to those identified in the App PP.<threats>
                <threat id="T.FLAWED_ADDON">
                    <description> Web browser functionality can be extended through the integration
                        of third-party utilities and tools. Malicious or vulnerable add-ons could
                        result in attacks against the system. Such attacks can allow unauthorized
                        access to sensitive information in the browser, unauthorized access to the
                        platform's file system, or even privilege escalation that enables
                        unauthorized access to other applications or the operating
                        system.</description>
                </threat>
                <threat id="T.SAME-ORIGIN_VIOLATION">
                    <description> Violating the same-origin policy is a specialized type of network
                        attack (covered generally as T.NETWORK_ATTACK in the App PP) which involves
                        web content violating access control policies enforced by a web browser to
                        separate the content of different web domains. It is specifically identified
                        as a threat to web browsers, since they implement the access control
                        policies that are violated in these attacks. <br/> Attacks which involve
                        same origin violations include: <ul>
                            <li>Insufficient protection of session tokens can lead to session
                                hijacking, where a token is captured and reused in order to gain the
                                privileges of the user who initiated the session.</li>
                            <li>Cross-site scripting (XSS) and Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF)
                                attacks are methods used to compromise user credentials (usually by
                                stealing the user's session token) to a web site. These attacks are
                                more likely a result of server security problems, but some browsers
                                incorporate technologies that try to detect the attacks.</li>
                            <li>Inadequate sandboxing of browser windows/tabs or a faulty cross
                                domain communications model can lead to leakage of content from one
                                domain in one window/tab to a different domain in a different
                                window/tab. Such attacks leverage the ability of browsers to display
                                content from multiple domains simultaneously.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </description>
                </threat>
            </threats>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter title="Security Objectives" id="sobj"> This Extended Package adds security objectives
        to those identified in the Protection Profile for Application Software (App PP). <section
            title="Security Objectives for the TOE" id="SecurityObjectivesTOE">
            <SOs>
                <SO id="O.DOMAIN_ISOLATION">
                    <description> To address the network attack associated with content leakage
                        between different web domains, the browser must ensure that content
                        originating from different domains (e.g., in a tab or iFrame) is properly
                        isolated. </description>
                    <component-refer ref="fdp_sop_ext.1"/>
                    <component-refer ref="fdp_acf_ext.1.1"/>
                </SO>
                <SO id="O.ADDON_INTEGRITY">
                    <description> To address issues associated with malicious or flawed add-ons,
                        conformant browsers implement mechanisms to ensure their integrity. This
                        includes verification and validation at installation time and update. </description>
                    <component-refer ref="fia_x509_ext.2.3"/>
                    <component-refer ref="fpt_tud_ext.2"/>
                </SO>
            </SOs>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter title="Security Requirements" id="req">This chapter describes the security requirements
        which have to be fulfilled by the browser. The browser must not rely on any third party
        add-ons to accomplish these requirements. Security requirements comprise functional
        components from Part 2 of <cite linkend="bibCC"/>. The following notations are used: <ul>
            <li>
                <b>Selection</b> (denoted by <i>italicized text</i>): is used to select one or more
                options provided by the [CC] in stating a requirement. Selections must be captured
                in the ST.<!-- Moved here from FDP_TRK as a global comment -->
            </li>
            <li>
                <b>Assignment</b> operation (denoted by <i>italicized text</i>): is used to assign a
                specific value to an unspecified parameter, such as the length of a password.
                Showing the value in square brackets indicates assignment.</li>
            <li>
                <b>Iteration</b> operation: are identified with a number inside parentheses (e.g.
                "(1)").</li>
        </ul>
        <section title="Security Functional Requirements" id="SFR">The Security Functional
            Requirements included in this section are derived from Part 2 of the Common Criteria for
            Information Technology Security Evaluation, Version 3.1, Revision 4, with additional
            extended functional components. <subsection title="Cryptographic Support (FCS)" id="fcs">
                <f-component id="FCS_STS_EXT.1" name="Strict Transport Security">
                    <f-element id="FCS_STS_EXT.1.1" status="objective">
                        <title>The browser shall implement HTTP Strict-Transport-Security according
                            to RFC 6797.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FCS_STS_EXT.1.2" status="objective">
                        <title>The browser shall retain persistent data signaling HSTS enablement
                            for the time span declared by the website in a max-age
                            directive.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FCS_STS_EXT.1.3" status="objective">
                        <title>The browser shall cache the "freshest" Strict Security policy
                            information.</title>
                        <note role="application"> Freshness refers to the length of time between
                            generation by the origin server and the expiration time when the origin
                            server specifies that a stored response can no longer be used by a cache
                            without further validation (RFCs 6797 and 7234). If a browser receives
                            the HSTS header from a website, all future HTTP sessions between the
                            browser and the domain or superdomain of that website must occur over
                            TLS 1.2 (RFC 5246) or greater by utilizing HTTPS (RFC 2818) negotiating
                            the strongest cipher possible. </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <tss> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it documents
                                how the browser supports HSTS. </tss>
                            <guidance> The evaluator shall examine the operational guidance to
                                ensure it contains instructions on how to use HSTS. </guidance>
                            <tests> The evaluator shall perform the following tests: <testlist>
                                    <test>The evaluator shall connect to a HSTS-compliant website
                                        while running a network protocol analyzer to monitor the
                                        traffic. The evaluator shall examine the captured network
                                        traffic and verify that a Strict Transport Security header
                                        is received and that there is a directive for the max-age of
                                        the HSTS relationship.</test>
                                    <test>The evaluator shall reconnect to the HSTS website again
                                        over HTTP and shall verify that the session is redirected to
                                        HTTPS.</test>
                                    <test>The evaluator shall reconnect to the HSTS website after
                                        the max-age has expired, and verify that the website and
                                        browser reestablish an HSTS relationship.</test>
                                    <test>The evaluator shall update the website HSTS information,
                                        and verify that when the browser reconnects to the website,
                                        that information is updated by the browser.</test>
                                </testlist>
                            </tests>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
            </subsection>
            <subsection title="User Data Protection (FDP)" id="fdp">
                <f-component id="FDP_ACF_EXT.1" name="Local and Session Storage Separation">
                    <f-element id="FDP_ACF_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The browser shall separate local (permanent) and session (ephemeral)
                            storage based on domain, protocol and port:<br/>
                            <ul>
                                <li>Session storage shall be accessible only from the originating
                                    window/tab;</li>
                                <li>Local storage shall only be accessible from windows/tabs running
                                    the same web application.</li>
                            </ul></title>
                        <note role="application"> The separation of local and session storage is
                            described in World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) Proposed Recommendation:
                            "Web Storage."<br/>
                            <!-- TERMS BELOW MOVED TO DEFINITIONS SECTION
                            In this context, a domain is a realm of
                            administrative autonomy, authority or control on the Internet (e.g.,
                            cnn.com, ietf.org). A sub-domain is denoted by a prefix before the
                            top-level domain name (e.g., news.cnn.com). A protocol is a system of
                            digital rules for data exchange within or between computers; in a web
                            environment, the typical protocols are HTTP and HTTPS. A port is an
                            application-specific construct that functions as a communications
                            endpoint in a computer's host OS; in a web environment, port 80 is the
                            default port for HTTP communications, although other ports can be used.
                            In a web address, the port follows the domain or sub-domain name (e.g.,
                            http://www.cnn.com:80). -->
                        </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes
                            how the TSF separates local and session storage. <h4>Guidance</h4> The
                            evaluator shall examine the operational guidance to verify that it
                            documents the location on the file system that will be used for local
                            storage and the location used for session storage. <br/>
                            <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator shall obtain or create JavaScript-based
                            scripts that store and retrieve information from local and session
                            storage and shall set up a web server with two or more web pages from
                            different domains <!-- clarified different domains --> using different
                            protocols and/or ports. The evaluator shall incorporate the scripts into
                            the web pages and shall perform the following tests:<br/>
                            <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall open two or more browser windows/tabs and
                                    navigate to the same web page. The evaluator shall verify that
                                    the script for accessing session storage that is running in one
                                    window/tab cannot access session storage associated with a
                                    different window/tab.</test>
                               <!-- Merged windows/tabs into test 1 
                                   <test>The evaluator shall open two or more browser tabs and navigate
                                    to the same web page. The evaluator shall verify that the script
                                    for accessing session storage that is running in one tab cannot
                                    access session storage associated with a different tab.</test> -->
                               <!-- Removed tests 3 and 4 because they appear more functionality rather than security related
                                   <test>The evaluator shall open two or more browser windows and
                                    navigate to the same web page. The evaluator shall verify that
                                    the script for accessing local storage that is running in one
                                    window can access local storage associated with a different
                                    window.</test>
                               <test>The evaluator shall open two or more browser tabs and navigate
                                    to the same web page. The evaluator shall verify that the script
                                    for accessing local storage that is running in one tab can
                                    access local storage associated with a different tab.</test> -->
                                <test>The evaluator shall open windows/tabs and navigate to
                                    different web pages. The evaluator shall verify that a script
                                    running in the context of one domain/protocol/port in a browser
                                    window/tab cannot access information associated with a different
                                    domain/protocol/port in a different window/tab.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FDP_COO_EXT.1" name="Cookie Blocking">
                    <f-element id="FDP_COO_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The browser shall provide the capability to block the storage of
                            third party cookies by websites.</title>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes
                            how the TSF blocks third party cookies and when the blocking occurs
                            (e.g., automatically, when blocking is enabled). <h4>Guidance</h4> The
                            evaluator shall examine the operational guidance to verify that it
                            provides a description of the configuration option for blocking of third
                            party cookies. <br/>
                            <!--Note added --> Note: For browsers on mobile devices, the following
                            tests require the developer to provide access to a test platform that
                            provides the evaluator with tools that are typically not found on
                            factory products. <br/>
                            <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator shall perform the following tests: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall clear all cookies and then configure the
                                    browser so that storage of third party cookies is allowed. The
                                    evaluator shall load a web page that stores a third party
                                    cookie. The evaluator shall navigate to the location where
                                    cookies are stored and shall verify that the cookie is
                                    present.</test>
                                <test>The evaluator shall clear all cookies and then configure the
                                    browser so that storage of third party cookies is blocked (i.e.
                                    not allowed). The evaluator shall load a web page that attempts
                                    to store a third party cookie and shall verify that the cookie
                                    was not stored.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FDP_PST_EXT.1" name="Storage of Persistent Information">
                    <f-element id="FDP_PST_EXT.1.1" status="optional">
                        <title>The browser shall provide the capability to operate without storing
                            persistent data to the file system.</title>
                        <note role="application"> Any data that persists after the browser closes,
                            including temporary files, is considered to be persistent data.
                            Exceptions from this requirement are credentials and configuration
                            information. </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify it describes
                            how the browser operates without storing persistent user data to the
                            file systems. <h4>Guidance</h4>
                            <!--Note added --> Note: For browsers on mobile devices, the following
                            tests require the developer to provide access to a test platform that
                            provides the evaluator with tools that are typically not found on
                            factory products. <br/>
                            <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator shall perform the following test: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall operate the browser for a period of time,
                                    ensuring that a wide variety of browser functionality has been
                                    exercised. The evaluator shall then examine the browser and the
                                    underlying platform to ensure that no files have been written to
                                    the file system other than credentials or configuration
                                    information.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FDP_SBX_EXT.1" name="Sandboxing of Rendering Processes">
                    <f-element id="FDP_SBX_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The browser shall ensure that web page rendering is performed in a
                            process that is restricted in the following manner: <ul>
                                <li>The rendering process cannot directly access the platform's file
                                    system;</li>
                                <li>The rendering process cannot directly invoke inter-process
                                    communication mechanisms with non-browser processes;</li>
                                <li>The rendering process has reduced privilege with respect to
                                    other browser processes <selectables>
                                        <selectable>[assignment: through methods by which the
                                            principle of least privilege is implemented for
                                            rendering processes]</selectable>
                                        <selectable>in no other ways</selectable>
                                    </selectables></li>
                            </ul>
                        </title>
                        <note role="application"> Web browsers implement a variety of methods to
                            ensure that the process that renders HTML and interprets JavaScript
                            operates in a constrained environment in order to reduce the risk that
                            the rendering process can be corrupted by the HTML or JavaScript it is
                            processing. This component requires the TSF to lower the privileges of
                            rendering processes by ensuring that it cannot directly access the file
                            system of the host, and that it cannot use IPC mechanisms provided by
                            the host to communicate with non-browser processes on the host.
                            Typically, if a rendering process needs to access a file or communicate
                            with a non-browser process, it must request such access through the TSF
                            (which is allowed by the requirement).<br/> In addition to the two
                            required measures, other measures can be implemented depending on the
                            browser and the host platform. These may involve such actions as
                            changing the owner of the rendering process to a low-privileged account
                            or dropping platform-defined privileges in the rendering process. The ST
                            author fills in the additional measures implemented by the browser. </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes
                            how the rendering of HTML and interpretation of JavaScript is performed
                            by the browser in terms of the platform processes that are involved
                            (with "process" being an active entity that executes code). For the
                            processes that render HTML or interpret JavaScript, the evaluator shall
                            examine the TSS to check that it describes how these processes are
                            prevented from accessing the platform file system. The evaluator shall
                            check the TSS to ensure it describes each platform-provided IPC
                            mechanism, and details for each mechanism how the rendering process is
                            unable to use it to communicate with non-browser processes. The
                            evaluator shall also confirm that the TSS describes how IPC and file
                            system access is enabled (if this capability is implemented); for
                            instance, through a more privileged browser process that does not
                            perform web page rendering. The evaluator shall ensure that these
                            descriptions are present for all platforms claimed in the ST.<br/> For
                            each additional mechanism listed in the third bullet of this component
                            by the ST author, the evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure 1) the
                            mechanisms are described; 2) the description of the mechanisms are
                            sufficiently detailed to determine that it contributes to the principle
                            of least privilege being implemented in the rendering process; and 3)
                            appropriate supporting information is provided in the TSS (or pointers
                            to such information are provided) that provides context for
                            understanding the claimed least privilege mechanisms. <h4>Guidance</h4>
                            The evaluator shall examine the operational guidance to determine that
                            it provides a description of the restrictions available on rendering
                            processes. Additionally, if such mechanisms are configurable (for
                            instance, if a user can choose which mechanisms to "turn on"), the
                            evaluator shall examine the operational guidance to ensure that the
                            method for enabling and disabling the mechanisms are provided, and the
                            consequences of such actions are described. <h4>Tests</h4>Note: The
                            following tests require the developer to provide access to a test
                            platform that provides the evaluator with debugging and test tools that
                            are typically not found on consumer platforms.<br/> The evaluator shall
                            perform the following tests on each platform claimed in the ST: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall use debugging or test facilities to
                                    introduce code into a rendering process that attempts to
                                    directly access the platform's file system, and then direct
                                    execution to it. The evaluator shall ensure that execution of
                                    this code fails to access the browser file system.</test>
                                <test>For each IPC mechanism described in the TSS, the evaluator
                                    shall use debugging or test facilities to introduce code into a
                                    rendering process that attempts to directly communicate with
                                    another non-browser process on the platform, and then direct
                                    execution to it. The evaluator shall ensure that this attempt
                                    fails.</test>
                                <test>For each additional mechanism claimed in the ST, the evaluator
                                    shall devise a test to show that the mechanism functions as
                                    described in the TSS. If no such test can be crafted, the
                                    evaluator shall provide a justification in the test report for
                                    why the mechanism cannot be tested.</test>
                                <test>For each mechanism that can be configured or turned on or off,
                                    the evaluator shall perform tests to ensure that the
                                    configuration of the mechanism behaves as specified in the
                                    operational guidance.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FDP_SOP_EXT.1" name="Same Origin Policy">
                    <f-element id="FDP_SOP_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The browser shall ensure that content retrieved from one origin
                            cannot interact with content retrieved from another origin without
                            consent from the origin whose content is being retrieved.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FDP_SOP_EXT.1.2">
                        <title>The browser shall not allow same origin policy exceptions for
                            different domains.</title>
                        <note role="application"> The Same Origin Policy concept is described in RFC
                            6454, "The Web Origin Concept."<br/> Origin is defined as the
                            combination of domain, protocol and port. Two URIs sharing the same
                            domain, protocol and port are considered to have the same origin. </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes
                            its implementation of a same origin policy and explains how it complies
                            with RFC 6454. If the TSF allows the relaxation of the same origin
                            policy for subdomains in different windows/tabs, the TSS shall describe
                            how these exceptions are implemented. <h4>Guidance</h4>
                            <br/>
                            <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator shall obtain or create scripts that can
                            retrieve content from designated locations and shall set up a web server
                            with two or more web pages representing different domains. The evaluator
                            shall incorporate the scripts into the web pages. The evaluator shall
                            associate each page with a different protocol and/or port and shall
                            perform tests 1 and 2.<br/> If the TSF supports relaxation of the same
                            origin policy for subdomains, the evaluator shall configure the web
                            server with subdomains and shall perform test 3 and repeat tests 1 and 2.<br/>
                            <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall open two or more browser windows/tabs and
                                    navigate to a different page on the website in each window/tab. The
                                    evaluator shall run the scripts and shall verify that the script
                                    that is running in one window/tab cannot access content that was
                                    retrieved in a different window/tab.</test>
                                <!-- Merged windows and tabs 
                                    <test>The evaluator shall open two or more browser tabs and navigate
                                    to a different page on the website in each tab. The evaluator
                                    shall run the scripts and shall verify that the script that is
                                    running in one tab cannot access content that was retrieved in a
                                    different tab.</test> -->
                                <test>The evaluator shall verify that the scripts can retrieve
                                    content from another window/tab at a different subdomain.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FDP_STR_EXT.1" name="Secure Transmission of Cookie Data">
                    <f-element id="FDP_STR_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The browser shall ensure that cookies containing the <i>secure</i>
                            attribute in the set-cookie header are sent over HTTPS.</title>
                        <note role="application">The set-cookie header functionality is described in
                            RFC 6265 <i>HTTP State Management Mechanism</i>.</note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify it describes
                            the browser‘s support for the "secure" attribute of the set-cookie
                            header in accordance with RFC 6265, including the required sending of
                            cookies containing this attribute over HTTPS. <h4>Guidance</h4>
                            <!--Note added --> Note: For browsers on mobile devices, the following
                            tests require the developer to provide access to a test platform that
                            provides the evaluator with tools that are typically not found on
                            factory products. <br/>
                            <br/>
                            <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall perform the following tests: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall connect the browser to a cookie-enabled
                                    test website implementing HTTPS and have the website present the
                                    browser with a "secure" cookie. The evaluator shall examine the
                                    browser‘s cookie cache and verify that that it contains the
                                    secure cookie.</test>
                                <test>The evaluator shall reconnect to the cookie-enabled website
                                    over an insecure channel and verify that no "secure" cookie is
                                    sent.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="fdp_trk_ext.1" name="Tracking Information Collection">
                    <f-element id="fdp_trk_ext.1.1">
                        <title>The browser shall provide notification to the user when tracking
                            information for
                                    <selectables><selectable>geolocation</selectable><selectable>browser
                                    history</selectable><selectable>browser
                                    preferences</selectable><selectable>browser
                                    statistics</selectable></selectables> is requested by a
                            website.</title>
                        <!-- Made this a global comment. 
                            <note role="application">Selections must be captured in the ST.</note> -->
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes
                            the TSF‘s support for tracking information and specifies the tracking
                            information that the browser allows websites to collect about the
                            browser user. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the
                            operational guidance to ensure it describes any notifications that the
                            user will receive when tracking information is requested by a website
                            and the options that the user has upon receiving the notification.
                                <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall perform the following tests for
                            each type of tracking information listed in the TSS: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall configure a website that requests the
                                    tracking information about the user and shall navigate to that
                                    website. The evaluator shall verify that the user is notified
                                    about the request for tracking information and that, upon
                                    consent, the web site retrieves the tracking information.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
            </subsection>
            <subsection title="Identification and Authentication (FIA)" id="fia">
                <f-component id="FIA_X509_EXT.2" name="X509 Certificate Authentication">
                    <f-element id="FIA_X509_EXT.2.3">
                        <title>The browser shall prevent installation of add-on code if the code
                            signing certificate is deemed invalid.</title>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it
                            describes how the browser chooses which certificates to use.<br/> The
                            evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it describes the behavior
                            of the browser or browser platform when a connection cannot be
                            established during the validity check of a certificate used in
                            establishing a trusted channel. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall
                            verify that any necessary instructions are contained in the operational
                            guidance for configuring the operating environment so that the browser
                            can use the certificates.<br/> If the requirement is that the
                            administrator is able to specify the default action, then the evaluator
                            shall ensure that the operational guidance contains instructions on how
                            this configuration action is performed. <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator
                            shall perform Test 1 for each function listed in FIA_X509_EXT.2.1 that
                            requires the use of certificates: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall demonstrate that using a certificate
                                    without a valid certification path results in the function
                                    failing or in the receipt of a user notification (as required by
                                    elements 3 and 4). The evaluator shall then load into the
                                    platform‘s root store any certificates needed to validate the
                                    certificate to be used in the function, and demonstrate that the
                                    function succeeds.</test>
                                <test>The evaluator shall demonstrate that using a valid certificate
                                    that requires certificate validation checking to be performed in
                                    at least some part by communicating with a non-browser IT
                                    entity. The evaluator shall then manipulate the environment so
                                    that the browser is unable to verify the validity of the
                                    certificate, and observe that the action selected in
                                    FIA_X509_EXT.2.2 is performed. If the selected action is
                                    administrator-configurable, then the evaluator shall follow the
                                    operational guidance to determine that all supported
                                    administrator-configurable options behave in their documented
                                    manner.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
            </subsection>
            <!-- Moved FMT to before FPT to match email client -->
            <subsection title="Security Management (FMT)" id="fmt">
                <f-component id="fmt_mof_ext.1" name="Management of Functions Behavior">
                    <f-element id="fmt_mof_ext.1.1">
                        <title>The browser shall restrict the ability to manage/perform functions as
                            follows:</title>
                        <ul>
                            <li>X = Mandatory</li>
                            <li>O = Optional</li></ul>
                        <table><tr class="header"><td>Management
                                    Function</td><td>Administrator</td><td>User</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>1. Enable/disable storage of third party
                                    cookies</td><td>O</td><td>X</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>2. Enable/disable individual
                                add-ons</td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>3. Enable/disable use of OCSP for obtaining the revocation
                                    status of an X.509 certificate</td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>4. Configure inclusion of user-agent information in HTTP
                                    headers</td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>5. Enable/disable ability for websites to collect tracking
                                    information about the user through <selectables>
                                        <selectable>zombie cookies</selectable>
                                        <selectable>add-on based tracking (e.g. Flash
                                            cookies)</selectable>
                                        <selectable>browsing history</selectable>
                                        <selectable>[assignment: other tracking
                                            mechanisms]</selectable></selectables></td><td>O</td><td>X</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>6. Deletion of stored browsing data (cache, web form
                                    information)</td><td>O</td><td>X</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>7. Enable/disable storage of sensitive information (e.g.,
                                    auto-fill, auto-complete) in persistent
                                    storage</td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>8. Configure size of cookie cache </td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>9. Configure size of cache </td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>10. Enable/disable interaction with Graphic Processing Units
                                    (GPUs)</td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>11. Configure the ability to advance to a web site with an
                                    invalid or unvalidated X.509
                                    certificate</td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>12. Enable/disable establishment of a trusted channel if the
                                    browser cannot establish a connection to determine the validity
                                    of a certificate </td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>13. Configure the use of an application reputation service to
                                    detect malicious applications prior to download
                                    </td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>14. Configure the use of a URL reputation service to detect
                                    sites that contain malware or phishing
                                    content</td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>15. Enable/disable automatic installation of software updates
                                    and patches</td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>16. Enable/disable ability for websites to register protocol
                                    handlers </td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>17. Enable/disable display notification when unsigned, untrusted
                                    or unverified mobile code is
                                    encountered</td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>18. Enable/disable user's ability to select default actions upon
                                    download of a file (e.g., always open, or always save, a
                                    downloaded file)</td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>19. Enable/disable launching of downloaded files outside the
                                    browser</td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>20. Enable/disable JavaScript</td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>21. Enable/disable <selectables><selectable>ActiveX</selectable>
                                        <selectable>Flash</selectable>
                                        <selectable>Java</selectable>
                                        <selectable>[assignment: other mobile code types supported
                                            by the browser]</selectable> mobile code</selectables>
                                </td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <!-- Address security aspect of Issue 22 by having the capability to prevent users from clicking through and ignoring error messages such as invalid cert-->
                            <tr><td>22. Enable/disable user's ability to acknowledge/accept risks
                                    associated with security warnings</td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                            <tr><td>23. Configure whitelist of trusted
                                    add-ons</td><td>O</td><td>O</td></tr>
                        </table>
                        <note role="application"> The intent of this requirement is to allow the
                            user and administrator of the platform to configure the browser with
                            configuration policies. If the administrator has not set a policy for a
                            particular function, the user may still perform that function.
                            Enforcement of the policy is done by the browser itself, or the browser
                            and its platform in coordination with each other.</note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall verify that the TSS describes those
                            management functions which may only be configured by the browser
                            platform administrator and cannot be over-ridden by the user when set
                            according to policy. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the
                            operational guidance to verify that it includes instructions for a
                            browser platform administrator to configure the functions listed in
                            FMT_MOF.1.1. <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall perform the following test:<br/>
                            <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall create policies that collectively include
                                    all management functions controlled by the browser platform
                                    administrator and cannot be over-ridden by the user as defined
                                    in FMT_MOF.1.1. The evaluator shall apply these policies to the
                                    browser, attempt to override each setting as the user, and
                                    verify that the TSF does not permit it.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
            </subsection>
            <subsection title="Protection of the TSF (FPT)" id="fpt">
                <f-component id="FPT_DNL_EXT.1" name="File Downloads">
                    <!--renamed from "Launch of Downloaded Executables" -->
                    <f-element id="FPT_DNL_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The browser shall prevent downloaded executables from launching
                            automatically.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FPT_DNL_EXT.1.2">
                        <title>The browser shall present the user with the option to either
                            <!-- download
                            or discard the executable -->
                            save or discard downloaded files.</title>
                        <note role="application"> This requirement ensures that if the user
                            intentionally (via clicking on a link) or unintentionally initiates the
                            download of a file, the TSF will intervene by, for example, opening a
                            dialog box that presents the user with the option to either save the
                            file to the file system or not download the file.<br/> In this context,
                            an executable is a file containing code for a software program that is
                            invoked independent of and outside the context of the browser. It does
                            not include mobile code, scripts, or add-ons.<br/>
                        </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure that it
                            describes the behavior of the TSF when a user initiates the download of
                            a file. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the operational
                            guidance to ensure it describes the dialog box that appears when a
                            download is initiated and the implications of the options presented by
                            the dialog box. <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall perform the following
                            tests: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall navigate to a website that hosts files for
                                    download including executables and shall attempt to download and
                                    open several of these files. The evaluator shall verify that the
                                    browser always presents a dialog box with the option to either
                                    download the file to the file system or to discard the
                                    file.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FPT_INT_EXT.1"
                    name="Interactions with Application Reputation Services">
                    <f-element id="FPT_INT_EXT.1.1" status="objective">
                        <title>The browser shall utilize an application reputation service to
                            prevent downloading of malicious applications.</title>
                        <note role="application"> An application reputation service is an online
                            service that identifies malicious applications; it is used to detect
                            such applications prior to downloading them.
                            <!-- 
                            Added to App Note. --> Using a
                            reputation service would require configuration of the trusted service to
                            be used. The quality of the reputation service may fall outside of the
                            scope of the evaluation.</note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes
                            the browser‘s use of application reputation services in detecting
                            malicious applications. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine
                            the operational guidance to ensure it describes the browser‘s support
                            for use of an application reputation service, including which services
                            the browser supports by default (if any) and whether additional services
                            can be configured. The operational guidance shall include steps for how
                            to configure the application reputation service. <h4>Tests</h4> The
                            evaluator shall perform the following tests: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall configure the browser to enable the use of
                                    one or more application reputation services per the operational
                                    guidance. The evaluator shall initiate a connection with a
                                    website that attempts to download an application to the browser
                                    while sniffing the network traffic using a network protocol
                                    analyzer. The evaluator shall inspect the captured network
                                    traffic and shall verify that the browser initiates a connection
                                    to the configured application reputation service(s) before
                                    initiating the download.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FPT_INT_EXT.2" name="Interactions with URL Reputation Services">
                    <f-element id="FPT_INT_EXT.2.1" status="objective">
                        <title>The browser shall utilize a URL reputation service to prevent
                            connections with malicious websites.</title>
                        <note role="application"> A URL reputation service is an online service that
                            identifies websites with malicious or phishing content applications; it
                            is used to detect such websites prior to allowing users to access them.
                            The goal of this requirement is to ensure that the browser is prevented
                            from establishing connections with known-bad sources of malware on the
                            Internet. The specifics of the sequence of actions taken before a block
                            decision is made may depend upon the specific implementation of the
                            browser. For example, some browsers might implement the check for
                            malicious content by checking against the list of bad URLs provided by
                            the URL reputation service in real time; others may download updated
                            lists of bad URLs at browser startup, updating the list periodically
                            from the URL reputation service(s) until the browser is terminated.
                            Ultimately, the result should be that the browser blocks the connection
                            to the bad URL. </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it describes
                            the TSF‘s use of a URL reputation service in detecting malicious
                            websites. <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the operational
                            guidance to ensure it describes the browser‘s support for use of URL
                            reputation services, including which services the browser supports by
                            default (if any) and whether additional services can be configured. The
                            operational guidance shall include steps for how to configure the URL
                            reputation service. <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator shall perform the
                            following tests: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall configure the browser to enable the use of
                                    one or more URL reputation services per the operational
                                    guidance. The evaluator shall initiate a connection with a known
                                    good website while sniffing the network traffic using a network
                                    protocol analyzer. The evaluator shall inspect the captured
                                    network traffic and shall verify that the browser initiates a
                                    connection to the configured URL reputation service(s).</test>
                                <test>The evaluator shall configure the browser to enable the use of
                                    one or more URL reputation services per the operational
                                    guidance. The evaluator shall initiate a connection with a known
                                    malicious website that is identified by one or more of the URL
                                    reputation services while sniffing the network traffic using a
                                    network protocol analyzer. The evaluator shall verify that a
                                    warning appears alerting that the website is known to be
                                    malicious and the browser is not allowed to connect. The
                                    evaluator shall inspect the captured network traffic and shall
                                    verify that the browser initiates a connection to the configured
                                    URL reputation service(s) and retrieved an updated list of
                                    malicious URLs with the tested website being on the list.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FPT_MCD_EXT.1" name="Mobile Code">
                    <f-element id="FPT_MCD_EXT.1.1">
                        <title>The browser shall support the capability to execute signed
                                <selectables linebreak="yes">
                                <selectable>ActiveX</selectable>
                                <selectable>Flash</selectable>
                                <selectable>Java</selectable>
                                <selectable>[assignment: other mobile code types supported by the
                                    browser]</selectable>
                                <!-- Added no (mobile code) selectable -->
                                <selectable>no</selectable>
                            </selectables>mobile code.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FPT_MCD_EXT.1.2">
                        <title>The browser shall provide the user with the option to discard
                            unsigned, untrusted or unverified <selectables linebreak="yes">
                                <selectable>Active X</selectable>
                                <selectable>Flash</selectable>
                                <selectable>Java</selectable>
                                <selectable>[assignment: other mobile code types supported by the
                                    browser]</selectable>
                            </selectables> mobile code without executing it.</title>
                        <note role="application"> The ST author must specify all mobile code types
                            for which the browser provides this support. <br/>An authorized signer
                            may directly sign the code itself, or the code may be delivered over an
                            authenticated HTTPS connection with an authorized entity. </note>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to ensure it lists the
                            types of signed mobile code that the TSF supports. The TSS shall
                            describe how the TSF handles unsigned mobile code, mobile code from an
                            untrusted source, and mobile code from an unverified source.
                                <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the operational
                            guidance to verify it provides configuration instructions for each of
                            the supported mobile code types. The operational guidance shall also
                            describe the alert that the browser displays to the user when unsigned,
                            untrusted, or unverified mobile code is encountered and the actions the
                            user can take. <h4>Tests</h4>The evaluator shall perform the following
                            tests for each mobile code type specified in the TSS: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall construct web pages containing unsigned,
                                    correctly authenticated, and incorrectly authenticated mobile
                                    code and ensure that the browser alerts the user when it
                                    encounters mobile code that fails to authenticate and provides
                                    the user with the option to discard the mobile code without
                                    executing it, but does execute mobile code that properly
                                    authenticates.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FPT_TUD_EXT.1" name="Support for Whitelisted Add-ons">
                    <f-element id="FPT_TUD_EXT.1.7">
                        <title>The browser shall include the capability to load <selectables>
                                <selectable>no add-ons</selectable>
                                <selectable>whitelisted add-ons</selectable>
                            </selectables>.</title>
                        <note role="application">The browser should support a mechanism that allows
                            individual add-ons to be added to a whitelist of trusted add-ons which
                            can be installed into the browser. Add-ons should be uniquely
                            identifiable down to specific versions so as to allow the list to only
                            allow specific versions of specific add-ons to be installed. This list
                            should be immutable to a user if it has been configured by an
                            administrator. Add-ons which are not present in the whitelist must not
                            be loaded into the browser.</note>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
                <f-component id="FPT_TUD_EXT.2" name="Trusted Installation and Updates for Add-ons">
                    <f-element id="FPT_TUD_EXT.2.1" status="sel-based">
                        <selection-depends req="FPT_TUD_EXT.1.7"/>
                        <title>The browser shall provide the ability to query the current version of
                            the add-on.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FPT_TUD_EXT.2.2" status="sel-based">
                        <selection-depends req="FPT_TUD_EXT.1.7"/>
                        <title>The browser shall provide the ability to initiate the downloading of
                            add-on updates.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FPT_TUD_EXT.2.3" status="sel-based">
                        <selection-depends req="FPT_TUD_EXT.1.7"/>
                        <title>The browser shall provide a means to verify add-ons using a digital
                            signature mechanism and <selectables>
                                <selectable>published hash</selectable>
                                <selectable>no other functions</selectable>
                            </selectables> prior to installing the add-on.</title>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="FPT_TUD_EXT.2.4" status="sel-based">
                        <selection-depends req="FPT_TUD_EXT.1.7"/>
                        <!-- <title>The browser shall prevent websites from automatically installing
                            add-ons.</title> -->
                        <title>The browser shall prevent websites from installing untrusted
                            add-ons.</title>
                        <aactivity>
                            <h4>TSS</h4> The evaluator shall examine the TSS to verify that it
                            states that the TSF will reject add-ons from unapproved sources.
                                <h4>Guidance</h4> The evaluator shall examine the operational
                            guidance to verify that it includes instructions on how to configure the
                            browser with trusted add-on sources. <h4>Tests</h4> The evaluator shall
                            perform the following tests: <testlist>
                                <test>The evaluator shall configure the browser with trusted add-on
                                    sources. The evaluator shall create or obtain an add-on signed
                                    by a trusted source and attempt to install it. The evaluator
                                    shall verify that the signature on the add-on is valid.</test>
                                <test>The evaluator shall create or obtain an add-on signed by an
                                    untrusted source and attempt to install it. The evaluator shall
                                    verify that the signed add-on is rejected.</test>
                                <test>The evaluator shall create or obtain an add-on signed with an
                                    invalid certificate and attempt to install it. The evaluator
                                    shall verify that the signed add-on is valid.</test>
                                <test>The evaluator shall create or obtain an add-on signed by a
                                    trusted source, modify the add-on without re-signing it, and
                                    attempt to install it. The evaluator shall verify that the
                                    signed add-on is rejected.</test>
                            </testlist>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
                </f-component>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <appendix title="Optional Requirements" id="optional"> The baseline requirements (those that
        must be performed by the web browser are contained in the main body of this EP.
        Additionally, there are three other types of requirements specified in <appref
            linkend="optional"/>, <appref linkend="sel-based"/>, and <appref linkend="objective"/>.
        The first type (in this Appendix) are requirements that can be included in the <abbr
            linkend="ST"/>, but are not required in order for a browser to claim conformance to this
        PP. The second type (in <appref linkend="sel-based"/>) are requirements based on selections
        in the body of the EP: if certain selections are made, then additional requirements in that
        appendix must be included. The third type (in <appref linkend="objective"/> are components
        that are not required in order to conform to this EP, but will be included in the baseline
        requirements in future versions of this EP, so adoption by vendors is encouraged. Note that
        the ST author is responsible for ensuring that requirements that may be associated with
        those in <appref linkend="optional"/>, <appref linkend="sel-based"/>, and <appref
            linkend="objective"/> but are not listed (e.g., FMT-type requirements) are also included
        in the ST.</appendix>
    <appendix title="Selection-Based Requirements" id="sel-based">As indicated in the introduction
        to this EP, the baseline requirements (those that must be performed by the browser or its
        underlying platform) are contained in the App PP and in the body of this EP. There are
        additional requirements based on selections from the App PP and/or in the body of the EP: if
        certain selections are made, then additional requirements below will need to be
        included.</appendix>
    <appendix title="Objective Requirements" id="objective"> This Annex includes requirements that
        specify security functionality which also addresses threats. The requirements are not
        currently mandated in the body of this EP as they describe security functionality not yet
        widely-available in commercial technology. However, these requirements may be included in
        the ST such that the browser is still conformant to this EP, and it is expected that they be
        included as soon as possible.</appendix>
    <appendix id="biblio" title="References">
        <bibliography>
            <entry id="bibCC">
                <tag>CC</tag>
                <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security Evaluation - <ul>
                        <li><a
                                href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART1V3.1R4.pdf"
                                >Part 1: Introduction and General Model</a>, CCMB-2012-09-001,
                            Version 3.1 Revision 4, September 2012.</li>
                        <li><a
                                href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART2V3.1R4.pdf"
                                >Part 2: Security Functional Components</a>, CCMB-2012-09-002,
                            Version 3.1 Revision 4, September 2012.</li>
                        <li><a
                                href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART3V3.1R4.pdf"
                                >Part 3: Security Assurance Components</a>, CCMB-2012-09-003,
                            Version 3.1 Revision 4, September 2012.</li>
                    </ul></description>
            </entry>
            <entry id="bibAppPP">
                <tag>AppPP</tag>
                <description>
                    <a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/pp/PP_APP_v1.1/">Protection Profile for
                        Application Software</a>
                </description>
            </entry>
        </bibliography>
    </appendix>
    <appendix title="Acronyms" id="acronyms">
        <acronyms>
            <entry>
                <term>AES</term>
                <description>Advanced Encryption Standard</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>CBC</term>
                <description>Cipher Block Chaining</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>CRL</term>
                <description>Certificate Revocation List</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>CSP</term>
                <description>Cryptographic Service Provider</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>CSRF</term>
                <description>Cross Site Request Forgery</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>DHE</term>
                <description>Diffie-Hellman Key Exchange</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>DN</term>
                <description>Distinguished Name</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>DSA</term>
                <description>Digital Signature Algorithm</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>DTLS</term>
                <description>Datagram Transport Layer Security</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>ECC</term>
                <description>Elliptic Curve Cryptography</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>ECDSA</term>
                <description>Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>EP</term>
                <description>Extended Package</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>FFC</term>
                <description>Finite-Field Cryptography</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>FIPS</term>
                <description>Federal Information Processing Standards</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>GCM</term>
                <description>Galois/Counter Mode</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>GPU</term>
                <description>Graphics Processing Unit</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>HMAC</term>
                <description>Keyed Hash Message Authentication Code</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>HTML</term>
                <description>HyperText Markup Language</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>HTML5</term>
                <description>HyperText Markup Language version 5</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>HTTP</term>
                <description>HyperText Transfer Protocol</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>HTTPS</term>
                <description>HyperText Transfer Protocol Secure</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>IETF</term>
                <description>Internet Engineering Task Force</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>IV</term>
                <description>Initialization Vector</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>KAT</term>
                <description>Known Answer Test</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>KDF</term>
                <description>Key Derivation Function</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>NIST</term>
                <description>National Institute of Standards and Technology</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>OCSP</term>
                <description>Online Certificate Status Protocol</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>OID</term>
                <description>Object Identifier</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>PDF</term>
                <description>Portable Document Format</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>rDSA</term>
                <description>RSA Digital Signature Algorithm</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>RFC</term>
                <description>Request for Comment (IETF)</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>RGB</term>
                <description>Random Bit Generator</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>RSA</term>
                <description>Rivest Shamir Adelman</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>SaaS</term>
                <description>Software as a Service</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>SHA</term>
                <description>Secure Hash Algorithm</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>SSL</term>
                <description>Secure Sockets Layer</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>TLS</term>
                <description>Transport Layer Security</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>W3C</term>
                <description>World Wide Web Consortium</description>
            </entry>
            <entry>
                <term>XSS</term>
                <description>Cross Site Scripting</description>
            </entry>
        </acronyms>
    </appendix>
</PP>
